[music]
Hey, are you
>> [music]
>> Heat.
Heat. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hello everybody. Good day, good evening
to everyone and welcome back to the Ask
Abij show. I hope you are all doing
great. It's been a while. Um I was uh
not here for a while. Last weekend I
wasn't there but we're back. We're back
and it's so good to be among you all. So
uh I'm going to take questions about
history today. I'm going to take
questions that you have asked in the
comments. I'll take as many of these as
possible. Before I do that, let me see
who all is there on the live chat and
greet some of you. I can see Nagendra
Adiga Aush Singh Shub Nationalist Ankita
Stone Chat DSP Manhattan Vikash PJ Super
Rex Vidi Manar Hello Random Skull Hello
Arhan Sutaria hello Vikash PJ Namaste
Mr. 88ers good evening Adi Tidi Anand
Bharadwaj Sumit Agarwal Ain Ashwani
Sagar Gare Namaskaram ultimate power sh
nationalist Mr. 88s geopolitical dubet
good to see you sir. Caitanya Manuja
Aush Singh Romesh Murugaya
Geopolitical Dubet is here from from
Indor uh painter good to see you super
hello stone Somi Jane is also here from
Jaipur. Super Rex Baskar Kayatwal Stone
Ashwani okay we are repeating a few
names here. Let's get on to some new
ones. Uh, Suresh, Sadwani, DJ, Divine
Joy, Parto Sharma, Parth, Event
Countdown, Duv Yadav, Shanks, Sorav,
Narayan, Unknown, Roads Talks, Subit
Agarwal,
Chundra, Shaker, Anoju, Art, Dianu
Singh, The Seeker, Hensy, Penguin.
Emergency episode soon. We'll see about
that if there's an emergency. Swapnil
saxa Nikkesh Dahal Santo Shana May Heoo
okay Vikash Savv Narayan Priyanka
Javalia hello freedom from outcome is
here from Canada good morning to you uh
Duvyadav Jagdish Mali hello Ojasitkumar
long time no see well we are back we're
back feminist hello Niranjan silent
viewer silent viewer hello Bushan
namaskar s Sharma DJ divine joy skr
Nikita Mashish The seeker, Sumit
Agarwal, this uh Avin Raalo Shva
Kandangal just some Nut Arhan Sutara. Um
who else? God was alive. Well, God was
alive. Good good to see that. Mir
Kulkarnney, Matt Reddi, Mlevvin, hello
DJ Divine Joy once again.
142 Yadesh Putdar
Himmanu Rajpurit Sharat Bandekar Bhoji
Akash Jayant Jayant Nahul Sharma uh
Mihir Kulkarnney Mr. Sakenna Aush Yadav
Pamel Nandi good to see you sir. Uh and
everyone else escala
Jami part Jesh Mali Sharat Adil Bance.
All right. Uh let me stop greeting you
all otherwise it will go on forever.
Let's take some questions. Uh Nikita
says what about a space special? Would
you like me to do a space special one of
these days? An episode only devoted to
space. the mysteries of space, the
mysteries of the universe. Maybe we'll
talk about aliens. Would you like that?
Let me know in the comments. Let me know
in the live. I won't be able to say the
live chat right now, but let me know in
the comments if it's something you want.
I will be very happy to do that. It's
one of my possibly my most favoriteest
of topics. I'll be happy to do it. Okay,
so let's get going with the questions.
What questions have I selected? I've
selected a bunch of questions. The the
thing is you all have asked such
incredibly fantastic wonderful questions
that one episode is not enough to to
field them all to handle them all. So
maybe I'm I'm really tempted to do
additional history specials to uh you
know handle all the questions. Okay,
let's get going with the questions. This
is not quite a history question but
let's begin with this one. Uh maybe it
will help others also you know
understand what I am about, what this
channel is about. So, this is by Alex
Martinez who says that I am a
conservative Portlander from from
Portland, Oregon, and I've been a
subscriber to your channel for a few
years now. I'm just curious about what
political views you share. Are you also
conservative? Are you a socialist? Just
want to clarify where you stand.
Sometimes it gets confusing to depict.
Yeah. Well, oh, first of all, thank you
for being here. Thank you for for
subscribing from Portland. Good to have
you. And it's a great question. I'm not
sure I've ever discussed this. Where do
I fit in? So, first of all, I don't
really fit US party labels. I don't map
neatly into American labels like
conservative or socialist or right or
left. I don't really fit into these
things. Uh some people would say that I
am a I'm an Indian nationalist. I I I
I've seen people, you know, on Reddit or
whatever talking about that that I'm an
Indian nationalist. Some people depict
me as a Hindu nationalist. What exactly
am I? I would say I am an Indian
civilizationalist.
I'm a civilizational realist. I believe
in realism. You have to be realistic
about the world. So I am a
civilizational realist. I am not
partisan. I don't necessarily support a
specific party, a specific uh person. I
support India. I support Indian
civilization.
Uh so and uh how do I judge ideas? How
do I judge
ideas? Essentially, I judge them based
on whether they strengthen or harm
India's sovereignty, India's competence,
India's long-term prosperity, India's
prospects for self-determination
long-term, India's long-term national
interest, India's long-term cultural and
civilizational interest. I I judge ideas
whether based on whether they whether
they strengthen or harm India's cultural
resilience cultural continuity
civilizational continuity civilizational
resilience essentially I am biased
towards India see a lot of people will
say that they are neutral I give you a
neutral perspective I will not say that
each one of us has some inherent biases
within ourselves and I am aware of that
the fact that I also am biased I am
biased towards India, India the
civilization state. That's what I'm
biased towards. So I that that's how I
that's how I uh you know evaluate ideas.
I that's how I judge ideas. How do I
judge or evaluate evaluate policy?
It's a simple test, you know. Does a
policy increase India's power, India's
resilience, India's freedom of action,
India's civilizational and cultural
interests and continuity over decades?
Not the next three weeks, next three
months, right? That sort of thing. And
what do I value?
Is it not necessarily political values,
but what do I value overall? I value
free inquiry. Yes, I I am aware that a
free speech and free inquiry should be
there. And I'm aware that they have
limitations in an in a real world.
That's called being realistic. But I do
value free inquiry. I uh I am all about
evidence first, labels second, right? Um
and if uh evidence changes then if the
data changes then my perspective also
changes. I'm open to changing my
perspective based on new data, new
evidence. I value I value merit which
means that I'm I'm opposed to
neverending affirmative action. I'm
opposed to never- ending reservations in
India. I I value strong defense for
India. I value resilience, resilient
supply chains. I value India's growth. I
value technological leadership and of
course I value India's culture and
civilization and I am very skeptical of
imported ideologies
and that sort of thing right so so based
on all of this there is some overlap
between where I stand and where American
conservatives will stand. Yeah. on
national strength, on deterrence, on on
maybe cultural continuity, cultural
values or whatever that is, right? So
there'll be some overlap there, but
there's going to be overlap with others
also uh you know based on maybe you know
industrial policy, technology etc. So uh
that's kind of where I where I stand. I
am an Indian civilizationalist. I I am a
civilizational realist and I am not
necessarily partisan. I don't
necessarily support one person, one
party, whatever. I support India and
which India, not the nation state, the
civilization state of which the nation
state is a subset. So of course I
support India, the nation in the shape
and form that it does exist today. But
broader in a from a broader perspective,
I I support India's civilization. So
that's kind of where I stand. Maybe to
some extent I'm conservative but to some
extent I you could say that I'm very
progressive. I'm very liberal. I used to
consider myself to be a liberal until I
until I discovered what liberal means in
the real world. Right? I'm not that
liberal. I do value you know different
ideas, different viewpoints, do
different perspectives. I do do value
plurality but not the kind of plurality
which says that you need to import all
you know people from all cultures, races
whatever in and put them in one place in
one city or in one country. Not that
sort of thing. I value the the beauty
and diversity of the world, the
plurality of the world and each culture
has its own place in the world. You
don't have to mix them all together.
That's how I see it. So maybe from that
perspective I may be a little bit
liberal but overall that's where I
stand. I am firmly with India with
Indian civilization and the Indian
national interest. So it doesn't fit
neatly into left or right in the US or
conservative versus uh socialist. I
definitely am not socialist.
I abhore socialism. Some ideas within
socialism may make a little bit of sense
in some contexts but overall socialism
is bad. It's ruinous as India knows very
well. So yeah, that's kind of where I
stand. I hope that clarifies things
maybe to maybe to a certain extent at
least. Anyway, thank you Alex. Good to
have you and thank you so much for being
a subscriber for several years. I really
appreciate that.
Right, next question.
Nirvana Shanks says, "How reliable are
historical narratives of conquest and
empire given that most surviving records
are produced by the victors?
Can we ever reconstruct a truly
objective past? You know, it's it's
difficult to construct an to even
construct a truly objective present
because even in the context of the
present moment right now, this very
second, there's like 50 different
narratives trying to influence the way
you see the world. So each person's
worldview even today about the way the
world is today is going to be shaped by
different narratives, competing
narratives. So it's different. It's it's
difficult to to even to construct a
truly objective present. First of all,
let's understand that because of the
power power of narratives and propaganda
and when it and you know you know the
great man Mr. Trump has uh you know
introduced this very famous uh uh you
know phrase or or or term which is
called what what fake news right fake
news
now if the news is fake imagine what
history is like today's news is fake we
know that a lot of it is is fake a lot
of it is is spun around a lot of it is
narratives a lot of it is is propaganda
so if the news is fake imagine how
history is going to be like. So there's
no question about the fact that
historical narratives of conquest,
empire, just history overall are
unreliable.
It's Napoleon I believe who said that
history is a set of lies agreed upon.
Isn't it?
So historical narratives whether they
are of conquest, whether they of empire,
whether they are of various nations,
civilizations, cultures, whatever these
are inherently shaped by [snorts] the
perspectives and intentions of those who
recorded them. Okay? And typically those
who recorded history and those records
if they have survived, these typically
are the records created by victors. the
ones who those who won uh you know
conquest, empire, whatever, right? The
the so these are so these historical
narratives what we call history these
are shaped by the perspectives and
intentions of those who won by the of
the victors and therefore they're going
to present they're going to it's it's a
guarantee that they will present a
skewed or selective version of events of
what really happened of how the world
was during that particular period of
time. whichever whichever period of time
we're looking at. So these historical
narratives are are influenced by
cultural biases for example, political
agendas,
power dynamics and so much more of the
victors of the dominant groups. So let's
say you have a conquered territory.
Let's talk about for example present day
Turkey,
right? So who won that? The Turks who
were central Asian invaders. They
conquered this land from the Greeks.
What we call Turkey today was
historically Greek in the Armenian
territory. It was it was the Armenians
and more than the Armenians, the Greeks
who lived in Anatolia and they coexisted
reasonably peacefully. And then you have
these invaders who come in and take over
the place. And I'll not go into the
history but they you know in in their
version of history is going to be very
different than the version of history
that the Greeks will put forth or the
Armenians will put forth. I mean the
Turks said that the Armenian genocide
never happened. There was no such thing
right and the Greek genocide obviously
that also never happened. Before the
Armenian genocide there were multiple
waves of Greek genocide which u I'm not
sure you will find any of that in in
world history textbooks. Greek genocide.
What about India?
What about India? What what happened in
the past 1,000 years,
right?
It's very controversial and nobody dares
to speak the truth.
Multiple waves of genocide of Indians.
First by the Turks, then by the
Europeans. The British engineered
hundreds of artificial famines in India.
We don't talk about that as a genocide.
We say it was the colonial period. It
was a period of foreign occupation,
British occupation, brutal, barbaric
British occupation of India. Can you see
the conflicting narratives here? What I
am saying is that it is not
colonization. Colon, it is not a
colonial period. It's a period of
brutal, barbaric, genocidal foreign
occupation.
But your history textbooks won't say
that. Your teachers won't say that. Your
professors won't say that. They'll wax
nostalgic about the British Raj, about
British colonialism, how the British
gave us railways. They gave us the
English language. They gave us tea and
they gave us uh justice, the judiciary
because we were so backward and barbaric
that we were living in trees, right? In
caves apparently.
So you see surviving. So the British
what they did is that they wrote the
history of India and that's what's
taught and in in today's schools and
colleges and and and universities or
various versions of what the British uh
wrote about India right what I mean
today you'll have Indian writers who
write about that but they base all of
that on the British writings about India
they have to put references in their
texts the references are all going to
you know point back to to what the
British wrote
for example, Sati all these narratives,
right? All these narratives and when
Indian writers write about this to to to
you know to debunk the atrocity
literature then they are tagged they
they they are labeled as this or that
Indian nationalists or Hindu were re
revisionists or whatever. Right?
So what the British wrote about India,
what the Turks say about Turkey, what
the Americans [snorts] write about their
conquest
of the Americas, what the Spanish write
about their conquest of the Americas,
what the British write about their
conquest of Australia and so much more.
What the Arabs write about whatever they
did and so on. All of this is what we
can consider to be surviving records of
history. And these surviving records
they always reflect the ideology and
justifications
of the victors.
They will glorify the achievements of
the victors. They will legitimize they
will seek to legitimize the rule
of the victors and they will vilify the
conquered peoples, the defeated peoples
and they will downplay all their
achievements if any. Right? and the the
the nations or cultures that have been
subjugated, conquered, those accounts,
you will find that they are lost. In the
case of India, our written records of
history are lost. They were burned by
the Turks a thousand years ago and
whatever survived, much of it was
destroyed by the by the British, right?
So or suppressed by the British.
So see today's India, we imagine it's a
free postindependence India,
right? We imagine that. There is this
great scholar called Dr. Bilal who
passed away sadly recently at the age of
I don't know nearly 100 hopefully 100 so
he is probably the world's greatest
archaeologist okay and he was the head
of the ASI and he he wrote more than 50
books articles whatn not about the
history of India that he uncovered
during his archaeological career more
than 50 books and so many papers and
whatnot how many of these books are part
of your college [clears throat] or
university curriculum today. None of
those. How many of Dr. Minaki Jane's
books are part of your uh college or
university curriculum? None of them.
Right? So you see all of this is
suppressed. These these uh
um you know this we are the subjugated
we we when it comes to the Turic and
British European perspectives, we are
the defeated people, right? We were
defeated by them and we were our land
was occupied by them. So we are the
subjugated group and our accounts will
be suppressed. Either they will be
destroyed, they will be lost
deliberately or they will be suppressed
and that's how history is the narrative
of history is controlled right it is
sanitized and because of this you'll
have massive gaps and asymmetries in the
evidence uh in the historical record
right so the official narratives the
what we have in our I mean if we are
genuinely independent and so on why do
we have The official narratives that are
so anti-India,
why do they frequently, not frequently,
why do they almost universally
omit the genocide, the atrocities, the
resistance that we put forth? Why do
they omit all of that almost
universally?
Right? So clearly historical narratives
are extremely skewed, extremely biased.
So how do we mitigate this bias? Right.
So what we can do is we have to compare
records from multiple sources. Don't
just look at what the British wrote. We
have records written by Indians also
that that are you know languishing in in
various uh temple repositories
that are languishing in in uh personal
family collections. Maybe some
universities have them but they are
gathering dust. Right? So you have to
compare records from multiple
perspectives. you to examine different
viewpoints, not just the viewpoint of
the of the oppressor, right? Uh you have
to uh take into account archaeological
evidence because archaeological evidence
is hard evidence,
right? And you also have to take into
account oral traditions. You can't
simply disregard or oral traditions. Why
should we disregard them?
If if a single person says that this is
my oral tradition, you may be skeptical.
But if if you have an oral tradition
that that comes forth from a wide area
let's say an entire state like Rajasthan
or or or let's say Hana or whatever it's
not just one person but everyone all the
old fox folks uh from in this region
they remember these accounts passed on
by their ancestors well then that's an
oral tradition and you can't disregard
that you have to put it in the correct
context right so that's called an
interdisciplinary approach you have to
combine historical uh data uh
uh literary data, archaeological data,
data from, you know, oral traditions.
And by doing that, it's like putting
together a jigsaw puzzle. And that helps
you reconstruct
aspects of the past that have been
overwritten, that have been uh, you
know, deleted, omitted, whatever, or
distorted or ignored. That's how we do
it. So, um,
that's the deal.
It it is a guarantee that each historian
is going to have some biases. Some of
them will know that I have this bias and
they will inform the reader that okay
I've written this but here are my
biases. I am so and so I'm Indian. I am
this is my religion. I'm Hindu or I'm
Jane or whatever and maybe you should be
aware of this so that this because
because my background may un knowingly
or unknowingly introduce some biases in
what I've written. So it's called fair
disclosure. Right? that sort of thing.
Uh so all historians operate within
they bring their own judgments, their
own perspectives into their work. They
operate within the current contemporary
cultural
framework. Right? And all of this it
inevitably is going to color to some
extent their interpretation of history.
So historians should transparently
acknowledge
these limitations, these, you know,
potential uncertainties in in what they
what they've written and potential and
and definitely the known uncertainties
in the available evidence and that's how
you do a fair job, a decent and
honorable job as a historian. But then
you ask yourself,
are India's historians doing this? an
honorable fair job of writing history.
Some are but the majority of the
so-called Dhbari historians they have
been essentially
playing the role of Gangadins
brown coolies. Someone once accused me
of being racist because I used the term
brown koolie. Hey, have you seen the
color of my skin? Can you be racist
towards yourself towards your own
people? Whatever. That's a different
story. we will not go there. So that is
the deal. Historical narratives are
extremely unreliable
and they usually reflect the biases and
perspectives
of the victors. And here's another
perspective.
Okay, before I end this answer,
see the Vikings,
they won a lot of the time. There was an
entire Viking age, right? in which they,
you know, repeatedly raided England,
eventually conquered England and ruled
England. And they were pretty
devastating. They were not big fans of
the Christian faith.
Okay? And uh they plundered uh Christian
um religious uh structies or whatever,
right? They plundered those. They killed
the monks and they they did such
terrible stuff over there, right? So how
come history is not written from the
Viking perspective?
Good question perhaps.
If they won, why did why is history not
written from their perspective? Because
afterwards they lost and they themselves
had to convert to Christianity. So at
the end of the day there was a Viking
age 200 plus years in which they were
they were supremely uh you know
supremely successful but eventually they
lost and they themselves had to convert
to Christianity and then it is the
Christians who proceeded to write the
history of the Viking age that's how
things go okay
Rohan Bidi says a couple of episodes ago
you elaborated on the details of the
Ashwab obey the yagna current I'm
currently reading the Mahabharat
Sanskrit Hindi edition by Gita press
considered to be the most authentic
version of the epic and I can confirm
everything you said about the yagna in
particular the animal sacrifice that was
spot on more than 300 animals were
killed were sacrificed in Udishir's
ashwagna including the horse that ran
across kingdoms its body is cut into
pieces and its fat is boiled in the
ritual for those who are interested
further details can be found in chapters
88 and 89 of the Anugita Parva volume 6.
I'm glad to have found a channel which
tells it like it is. No sugar coating,
no BS. Been following you since your
first book recommendations video when
you had short hair. Ron Bei, thank you
so much for being uh one of the earliest
viewers of this channel and for sticking
with the channel with me. I really
really appreciate that. I'm very
grateful to you and others like you. I'm
very grateful to all the viewers of this
channel for all your support for your
viewership. Uh and when it comes to what
you're saying about the Ashwamed Yagna,
more than 300 animals were killed. Well,
a this will make a lot of today's
Indians super uncomfortable.
Many of my viewers right now are perhaps
feeling very upset about this, maybe
feeling angry about this. Maybe some of
them are wondering whether the
translation is correct or whether
somebody has distorted the translation.
Right?
The past was a long time ago. We are
talking about some an event that
happened several thousand years ago.
If you read the riga,
does it say that you should be
vegetarian? Does it extol the virtues of
vegetarianism?
Um, it does not. FYI.
Okay. And if you look at the Indian
epics, the great our great epics, the
Ramayan and the Mahabharat, you will
have references to animal sacrifices, to
animals being consumed,
etc.
So, your ancestors had a different
lifestyle from yours. The core values of
our culture and civilization haven't
changed,
but some things have changed. And I
suppose in that episode I I explained
how this transition happened from India
being a primarily meat eating society
several thousand years ago to
transitioning towards being a
predominantly vegetarian society about 2
and a half thousand years ago because of
the sudden
and um inorganic
upsurge or or rise in Buddhism
in India. spread the sudden spread of
Buddhism in India. It did not spread
naturally or organically. It spread
artificially. Buddhism was was
essentially,
you know, thrust onto the masses
artificially. By whom? By the great man
himself, Emperor Ashoke, not Akbar,
Ashoke. He did that. Buddhism was an
obscure uh branch of the Dharmic
umbrella of the Dharmic tree. And Ashok
for political reasons decided to promote
Buddhism to the high heavens. And uh
that's how Buddhism became a big deal.
And then the Buddhists started accusing
you know non Buddhists of being uh
animal killers especially Brahmin
priests etc of being animal killers. You
guys sacrifice animals in your jagnas
you are monsters. Because of that for
tactical reasons brahinss decided that
we will become completely vegetarian.
The Buddhists were still meat eaters to
some extent. They did not do yagnas but
they were meat eaters. The Brahman said
we will
do do better than you. We will become
completely vegetarian. And that's how
Hindus become started becoming
vegetarian. Eventually Hindu Hinduism
made a comeback. The main Hindu dharma.
But there was a period of several
centuries when both the dharma was the
majority
was practiced by the majority of
Indians. I'm sure we all have ancestors
about 2,000 plus years ago who practiced
Buddhism both the dharma but we reverted
eventually to the the
broader aspects of uh what we now call
Hindu dharma but that came with the
baggage of vegetarianism and that's how
we became like all ainsa ainsa all
vegetarianism and so on and maybe it
wasn't the best thing to happen to us
perhaps I'm sure a lot of you will
disagree uh and And that's fine. That's
fine. Please feel free to disagree. We
can have different perspectives but
still be on the same boat and still go
in the same direction. We should be
comfortable with disagreeing with each
other on these smaller matters. All
right. Next question.
Shou says um Shub says how did South
Korea become a vasal of the United
States and both the Dharma or Buddhism
so-called Buddhism. How was it wiped out
from South Korea? Didn't the South
Koreans resist
this uh the wiping out of the indigenous
culture and religion Buddhism? So
this all goes back to the Korean War.
Now let's discuss the Korean War and we
will then discuss what happened to Korea
as in the aftermath of the Korean War.
So the Korean war it uh
so in 1945 let's start there in 1945 the
the second world war ends let's take a
look at the map of the Korean peninsula
and we shall uh base our discussion on
on that first let's orient ourselves
so let us uh go eastwards from India and
there over here we have the Korean
peninsula we have which is now divided
into North Korea and South Korea
the 38th parallel. If you put a marker
here, it's going to say 38 point
something, right? That's 38th parallel
latitude. And that's the the de facto
border between North and South Korea.
So, what happened is that in 1945, the
Second World War ended with the two
nuclear tests on the people of Japan by
the United States. Germany had been
defeated a few months before. So, the
Second World War, Second World War ends
at this time. Who's the ruler of the
USSR? It is Joseph Stalin. And at this
time, what's the situation in China in
1945? Civil war between the communists
and the Kintang. The communists are led
by Maatong and the Kintan is led by
Chunkaek. Okay, that's deal. So
when the second world war ended, the
Korean peninsula was divided into two
halves. North Korea which was
interested to the USSR and South Korea
which was let's say let's say interested
maybe not the right term but you get the
point which was interested South Korea
to the United States okay and at this
point in time in 1945 the two nations
the US and USSR are allies so no so
North Korea is in the hands of USSR
South Korea is in the hands of the US
and they said that okay and and they
divided this along the 38th parallel
roughly or maybe that happened Here we
can look into the exact chronology and
the peninsula would it was decided it
would be uh reunited after discussions
but then the cold war starts and the US
and the USSR become adversaries very
rapidly.
By roughly 1950 the USSR becomes a
nuclear power, nuclear weapons power. So
it kind of establishes some kind of uh
uh some kind of equality to some extent
with the United States and the USSR is a
Eurasian uh empire essentially. The US
is a different kind of empire. So then
North and South Korea they become in
they are in the hands of of rivals of
enemies essentially and by 1949 what
happens the communists win in China in
Maong [clears throat] is is victorious
and they establish you know the rep
whatever it's called China war
now at this time North Korea was ruled
by Kim Ilsung and South Korea had some
puppet ruler of the US. These are both
puppets. Kiml Sunsung is the puppet of
the USSR and whoever was ruling South
Korea was a puppet of the US. Now Kim
Sunung he is emboldened by the communist
victory in China. North of China you
have the USSR which is also communist.
So Kimlong says that let us make the
whole of Korea communist and let's
attack South Korea. So the USSR says
okay.
Stalin says okay do it but take Mao's
permission if he's okay with the plan I
will give you the green light green flag
yeah so Kimlong speaks to Mao and Mao
says okay go ahead let's make whole of
the whole of South Korea communist and
Kimlong invades South Korea the USSR
gives North Korea
Mig 15 fighter planes and arms
ammunition but does not send soldiers
Stalin Stalin refused to send soldiers
but gave all of these supplies you know
military supplies powerful military
weapons to North Korea and the Chinese
they sent soldiers disguised as you know
not official Chinese soldiers but in
some other some other guys and you have
in 1950 the war breaks out North Korea
invades the south and then in 1950 and
1951 these two years there's this
seessaw battle across the Korean
peninsula there is a point of time When
the South Koreans are almost wiped out,
then the Americans come into the
picture, they send large amounts of
troops. Eventually, the Americans send
about 300,000 troops, American American
soldiers to the into the Korean War and
the Americans come into the picture.
Then the South Koreans start advancing
and North Korea is almost wiped out when
then they research again with the help
of the Chinese. the Chinese soldiers
come into the picture and there's this
this seesaw battle seesaw battle happens
in 1950 1951 [clears throat] by 1952 or
something like that what happens is that
you know the war becomes a slow war long
war campaign
a slow war long war scenario like what
you have in Ukraine right now so in
after 1951 you have the two uh North and
South Korea they're fighting each other
like they used to fight in the first
world war, trench warfare,
massive charges, tremendous casualties,
that sort of thing and it becomes kind
of a frozen conflict.
Then around 1953 Stalin dies
and then Nikkita Kush says that we need
to
extricate ourselves from this imbugo
and then you have you know negotiations
happen and eventually a cease not a
cease yeah ceasefire is agreed upon
armistice of some kind and the the line
is drawn at the 38th parallel roughly
and it became the ceasefire line there
was this no man's land kind of thing
constructed which is 3 4 kilometers wide
and the so-called demilitarized zone
between North and South Korea.
Okay. Now and and so that's how the war
ended without ending because there was
no official end to the war. It is still
the two nations are still in a state of
war but it's a ceasefire kind of
situation since the what 1953
approximately.
So that's what happened in the Korean
war and that's how North as well as
South Korea were devastated
devastated
um approximately 10 to 15% of the
population of the peninsula Korean
peninsula died which is disastrous
disastrous for any nation right
um so at the end so when the Korean war
begins okay um South Korea probably had
a population of about 20 million. I'm
not sure about the North Korean
population. So the Korean War began in
1950. At that time, South Korea had a
population of approximately 20 million
and 10 to 15% of that those people died,
which is about 2 to 3 million.
Let's say 3 million South Koreans died.
That is devastating. Okay. Now, when the
war ended,
the Americans established a large number
of military bases. They had already
established during the course of the war
a large number of military bases in
South Korea and those remained. So today
you have more than 80 you could say
active or permanent American military
bases in South Korea. Um and the largest
American military base outside of the US
is Camp Afrey's
which uh which has about I don't know it
can hold about 30,000 troops or
something right. So that's it's it's not
far from from soul in South Korea.
So South Korea was devastated. It was
ruined.
It was in a state of famine,
abject poverty. And then South Korea
also becomes a dictatorship and within a
few decades they set up this big
industrial base with the help of the
United States. The US did all it could
to build up South Korea. Um and uh South
Korea at that time its GDP would have
been less than 50 million. 50 million
not billion okay 50 million it GDP would
have been less than 50 million when this
when the Korean war ended and today it's
in excess of 1.5 trillion. So it's made
a huge huge huge leap forward. Now what
about the end of Buddhism?
So if you
so in 1950 what was the percentage of
Christians in South Korea? You may have
maybe one and a half million Christians
out of the population of 20 million in
1950. Um that's not a small number
actually
but that 1.5 million in 1950 Christians
it it became about 6 million by 1970.
Okay 6 million by 1970. And today it is
about 15 million um or maybe more. So
from 1950 to 1970 the population of
Christians tripled. From 1970 to 2000
the population of Christians tripled
once again. And today uh Christians are
more than 30% of the South Korean
population officially and Buddhists are
about 17% or so. How did this happen is
the question. You see at the end of the
Korean war 1953, South Korea is
devastated. Is it is ruined. It's an
abject poverty.
So the Christian missionary
organizations come into South Korea and
they start giving aid to people. They
give people rice. They give people
shelter. They help people send their
kids to Christian schools and so on. But
obviously there's a trade-off. Rice
isn't free.
Yeah, it'll be free, but you have to
sell your soul for that. So, you have to
convert to Christianity. It's the same
old story that the Chinese wrote about
in the 1850s.
China was ruined during those horrible
horrible times in China, the Dungan
revolt uh and so on.
And the evangelists would come into
China and offer rice in in in in
exchange for conversion. And the Chinese
wrote about this and they called those
converts rice Christians. Well, the same
strategy was used in Korea as well by
the Americans. Right? So that is how
South Korea not only became a vasal of
the US, it also
you know it's its indigenous religion
was also wiped out. Now you may say that
that Buddhism has come from India. It's
not indigenous to South Korea or or
Korea overall. It's been in Korea for
the best part of 2,000 years. that makes
it indigenous. If it's been in your
country for 20 years, it's foreign. If
it's been in your country for let's say
even a thousand years, if it is being
imposed on your country by force, it's
foreign.
It's invasive.
But if the people have willingly adopted
it and and you know made it their way of
life, willingly without any coercion,
without any force, then it's your cure.
So South Korea's, you know, native
culture the past roughly 2,000 years has
been Buddhism and that that is now being
wiped out. So today, Christianity is the
majority religion. The rest are
apparently atheists. And today you will
see South Korean tourists coming into
the Indian subcontinent and trying on
tourist visas and trying to convert
Indians uh to Christianity. Nepalese
also that's what you see happening. So
that is the deal. That is how all of
this happened. So the US has more than
um 80 essentially permanent military
bases in South Korea. South Korea is
under US occupation since 1953 maybe
before that. And um that's how South
Korea became an American basal and
that's how Christianity essentially is
in the process of wiping out South
Korea's indigenous religion which is
Buddhism.
All right.
Amisha says, "What's the reason for
Bactria and Margana as a classification?
What's unique about this culture?" See,
Bactria, Marg Marana,
these are not cultures. These are
geographical regions. So, let us go to
the map and let's figure out what's
going on. Okay. Um, here's the map and
let us move back to the subcontinent. We
talking about the extended neighborhood
of the of of our subcontinent. So what
is Bactrea first of all? So before we
discuss Bactria, let us discuss Gandhar
to orient ourselves. What is Gandhar or
what was Gandhar historically? Gandhar
historically was Afghanistan. What we
call today Afghanistan and also the
northern northwestern part of of
Pakistan. All of this huge large region
was called Gandhar historically by us
including the ancestors of the Afghans.
They were also us. Okay. So that is
historically Gandhar and it was a major
center of Indian culture, Vic culture
and later Buddhist culture and uh at
various points in time Gandhar was part
of the Persian Empire, the Akamanish
Empire. It was also obviously part of
Indian civilization. It was also part of
the Morian Empire. It was part of the
Indo- Greek kingdoms. It was part of the
great Kushan Empire. Later it became
part of the Casanian kingdoms and so on.
Right? So that is Gandhar. Eventually it
came to be known as Sarasthan which
became Horasan and then eventually
Afghanistan. So that is Gandhar. Now
that we understand what Gandhara is, let
us discuss Bactria and Marjana. So
Bactria is the region the Greeks gave
this name if I'm not mistaken and that
is the northern half essentially of
Afghanistan which which also includes
Usbakistan and Tajakistan.
So Tajakistan is a small country just
northwest of India and you also have uh
Usbakistan which is west of Tajakistan.
So it in so bacteria included northern
Afghanistan. It also included Tajakistan
and parts of Usbakistan and probably
some parts of Turk Menistan also. So
that is Bactrea and this was also part
of the Indo- Greek kingdoms. Okay.
Alexander kind of was in the region
briefly. Um and after the fall of the
Seucid Empire, you had these this whole
bunch of Indo- Greek kingdoms that that
popped up in the region. So those were
Greeks who had assimilated into Indian
society and uh so so Bactria was the
home of multiple Indo- Greek kingdoms.
It was also very much part of the great
Kushan Empire and it gave us the great
uh you know the Gandhara school of art
the Hellenistic
u you know depictions of Indian culture
and it was a great center of knowledge
and learning and also a great crossroads
of trade between India and the west and
also to some extent China. So that is
bactria. Now what is margana?
So there is something called the Morgab
River Oasis. Let's look for that. Morgab
River
Oasis.
Let's look for that. It is in Turk
Menistan. Now let's zoom out. Let's zoom
out. Let's zoom out. Let's zoom out.
Right. So it is in present day Turk
Menistan.
And this place Morgab was the epicenter
or or essentially the roughly the center
of this place this territory that was
called Margana. Okay, it is not a very
large territory and it was called
Margana. So it kind of overlaps to some
extent with northern Bactria. It was
part of the Akameid or Empire of Persia.
Um and u so that that essentially is is
marginana. It is kind of a subset of
bacteria but it kind of includes regions
that are north of bactrea. Then you also
have names such as aracosia. What is
aracosia?
So Aosia is essentially southern
Afghanistan. Where is kandahar? Let's
let's find kandahar. You see kandahar.
So this region called Arakosia was kind
of centered around Kandahar. Okay. And
it also encompassed various parts of
Pakistan as well. So that was Araosia
and it was essentially named after the
river Saraspati.
If you distort the name of Saraspati, it
somehow transforms into Araosia.
And uh you also had Korasan which is you
know Afghanistan later became known as
Swarathan.
which included present day Afghanistan
also northeastern Iran as you see as you
see over here u Turkmanistan the
southern part of Turkmanistan
and uh
much of Afghanistan so that was Sarasan
which later became Horasan
um and that also was part of the various
Persian kingdoms like the Cassenian
kingdoms so that essentially it's it's
pretty confusing I stand but these are
the various names that have been given
to our extended neighborhood including
territories that were once part of
Indian civilization. So that is Bactria
Majana and there you have this BMAC
Bactria Majana archaeological complex
which uh is this set of ancient ruins
that you find there and you have
supposedly [laughter] a culture which
was separate from ours over there and
that has some connotations and you know
some alleged implications for the Arian
invasion or migration myth. So anyway
that that's about Bactrea and Margia.
Now Amisha also asks what happened to
the Greeks of Bactrea and when did the
last Helens or Greeks die out. So we
discussed Bactrea
which is northern Afghanistan,
Turkmanistan and Tajakistan also.
So and that's where you had the Indo
Greek kingdoms which also encompassed
you know northwest India, Pakistan etc.
So what happened to these Greeks? Where
did they go? When did the last Greeks
die out? Because today if you look at
northern India, Western India, Pakistan,
Afghanistan, you don't see any Greek
people there.
You see some people who have blonde hair
and blue eyes. And are they Greeks? I
mean, go to Greece. How many blonde and
blue-eyed Greeks do you see in Greece?
Most Greeks have dark hair and brown
eyes.
Hm. So if you find some people small
tiny populations here and there in Swat
in Chetal
um in some parts of Afghanistan who have
blonde hair and blue eyes.
It is not a connection to Greece. Okay.
First of all that so those are not the
descendants of the Indo- Greeks. The
question is what happened to the Indo
Greeks? When did they die out? Because
we don't find any of them in northern
India. I mean let's call it northern
India. What happened to them? So
remember the Indo Greeks are called the
Indo- Greeks.
They were not Greeks. They were Indo-
Greeks. What does Indogreek mean? It
means that they had assimilated into
Indian society, culture and
civilization. They had become culturally
Indian. And more than that, they would
have married among the locals.
For example, we have the great king
Milinda Minander
who was a great scholar of the Vedas who
later allegedly converted to both the
dharma, Buddhism.
His capital was Shakala present day.
Seial Kot. Where is Seial Kot? Let us
find Seial Kot. Let's uh go to the map
once again. Where is Seial Kot?
Where is Seial Kot? It's somewhere in
here we have it. It's not far from
Jammu. So he had a big kingdom. He
eventually made a march on Patliputra
you know uh Milinda Milandander and
eventually it is said that he allegedly
converted to Buddhism but he was I mean
if you think I'm making it up let's
let's go to let's see let's see I don't
know what Wikipedia says about him. Let
us see what Wikipedia says about him.
Okay. Minander
Minander the first. Okay. great king um
patron of Greek or Buddhism blah blah
blah uh etc king of bactrea rai river
helman province all that yeah can his
coins milindapana theak question so the
milindabana is this apocryphal Buddhist
text I'm not even sure if we can trust
that text because if you see his coinage
you don't see much Buddhism on on in his
coinage it is said that the Kushans were
Buddhists right
before I go into this it is alleged
that the Kushans
our great emperors were Buddhists. It is
said that Kaneshka was a Buddhist right.
There is a tremendous quantity of Kushan
coinage that has been discovered gold
coinage, bronze coinage etc coinage.
And on Kushan coins you typically have
on one side of the coin you have an
image of the king doing something great.
On the other side of the coin, you have
a god, a deity.
And there's a tremendous quantity of
Koshan coinage that has that exists in
various museums and private collections
and smuggler smuggled collections and
whatnot. If you do a statistical
analysis of the Kushan coinage, less
than 1% of Kushan coins have the Buddha
or Buddhist imagery. So how can you
allege or claim that the Kushans were
Buddhists? Similarly, there's a big
question about Manandra as well, but
that's a different different story. So
Minander uh Buddhist construction milind
the panha Buddhism etc. Men under the
just
does it say here that he was a Vic
scholar ve
four Vedas. There you have it. So there
you go. So the great man he
he knew uh the sananka yoga naya vesic
system of philosophy arithmetic music
medicine. He was a learned person. Magic
spells apparently uh the Vedas, the
piranhas, the iHihas, astronomy, ma
magic, the art of war, poetry and so
much more. So Minander, my point is not
about the conversion, alleged conversion
to Buddhism or not. My point is Minander
was Indian. He may have had Greek
ancestry. Maybe he was full-blood Greek
himself, but he was Indian culturally
and civilizationally.
And these Greeks, these Indo Greeks,
they married among Indians. So Greek
ladies would have married Indian men and
Greek men would have married married
Indian ladies. So what happens then?
Eventually they assimilate into the
local population eventually after like
five 10 generations. You can you can't
tell anymore
whether they have Greek ancestry or not.
They did not die out.
They simply faded into the population.
They assimilated into the population.
They intermarried into the population.
And after multiple generations, no one
could tell who was of Greek origin, who
was not. That is what happened. They did
not die out or they and they did not go
back to Greece after the the kingdoms
are gone. No, they just be stayed there.
So if you do a sampling perhaps genetic
sampling of people in northern and
western India including um Gandhar and
Pakistan,
you may discover fractional Greek
ancestry, one person, two person Greek
ancestry among various people.
But you will not be able to tell by
looking at them. Right? You won't.
That's what happened to the Greeks of
Bactria.
Right? Rahul Dunke says, "Who was
morally correct in the Trojan war? Was
Hector more moral than Achilles?"
Achilles as Hector was defending his
city and the Greek Achilles was invading
it.
Very interesting question. First of all,
let's go to the map. Did this Trojan war
actually happen or is it a myth? Will it
actually happen? It happened around the
12th or 13th century BC. Where did it
happen? I could tell you where it
happened because the city, the site of
Troy has been discovered. It is
currently in Turkey in western Turkey,
not far from Smyrna. I refuse to call
Ismir Ismir. I call it Smyrna. So, where
is Hisarlic?
His Turkey. Turkey. I Turkey. There we
go. And zoom [clears throat] in. So,
let's zoom out first and let's see where
it is. His
all right. It's here. Okay. It's not
very close to Ismir, but apparently this
is where Hisarik is. And if you look at
the
So, Hisarlic is the actual uh
archaeological site of Troy.
And uh this is I'm sure there's that's
the archeological site somewhere here.
Um it's all in Turkish so I can't really
make out what it says. Elementary school
um his Troy Troy. Let's see. Troy
will this Okay, it's somewhere here.
Okay. So, you have an archaeological
site that has been discovered which
apparently which which definitely has
been identified as the site of Troy.
I'm very skeptical. It'll be like
hundreds of kilometers in land. As far
as I know, it's somewhere here in this
region.
Let's see if we just look for Troy. pro
archaeological
site.
Okay. I I think for some reason it won't
show us what we're looking for. That's
okay. The point is Troy has been
discovered. The archaeological site of
Troy has been discovered. It is in
western Turkey. Okay.
and the the Trojan war based on
archaeological evidence of of battles
and you know burnt out structures and so
on.
It most likely happened in the somewhere
around the 12th or 13th century BC in
the Bronze Age.
Now what caused the Trojan War? Let's
let's discuss that.
What caused the Trojan War? So there's a
mythological element to it and maybe
there's a different element to it as
well. The mythological element says that
there were three Greek goddesses
who
were unable to agree who was the fairest
of them all. Who was the most beautiful
among these among the three of them? It
was Hira, Athena and Aphroditi.
These three goddesses they had this
disagreement. Each said, I am the
prettiest. I am the most beautiful. So
they decided that they will appoint an
impartial adjudicator.
And that was Paris, the prince of Troy.
So there was this golden apple that they
gave him. It's called the apple of
discord. And uh so Paris, who was the
prince of Troy, was chosen to decide to
judge who was the most beautiful of
these three goddesses. And he decided he
said that Aphroditi is the fairest and
most beautiful of these three goddesses.
So Aphrodite obviously was very pleased
with him. And she promised him that he
would gain the love of the world's most
beautiful woman who was Helen. Helen of
Troy. Okay. Helen of Yeah. Helen
eventually came to be known as Helen of
Troy, but she was the queen of Sparta.
She was married to King Menelaus of
Sparta.
So
Paris,
he either abducts Helen or maybe he
elopes with Helen. So we're not quite
sure whether Helen went with Paris
willingly or unwillingly. If she went
unwillingly then she was abducted. If
she went willingly then she was the
eloped essentially. So he let's say
elopes elopes with Helen who was married
to the king of Sparta King Menelaus and
he takes her to Troy. So Menelos
obviously is this is a great insult to
him isn't it? Right. Great insult. I
mean his reputation is ruined. His
reputation is on on the line. So he then
calls upon his brother Akamenon and he
calls upon other Greek leaders. He says
that we have to recover Helen from
across the sea from Troy. This is a
great insult to us the Greeks.
Okay. So they agree. His brother agrees
and the other Greek leaders they agree.
So they assemble a great Greek
expedition force, hundreds of ships
potentially, and they launch this
expedition to conquer Troy. [snorts] And
then there is a great siege of Troy.
Troy was on the seashore. Right now it's
a few kilometers indoors because, you
know, coastlines change. This happened
almost 3,200 years ago. So they led this
Greek expedition. They besieged the city
of Troy. There were battles that
happened outside the the walls of Troy.
And eventually we know after 10 after a
decade or so after 10 years of the siege
they eventually succeeded with the help
of the Trojan horse. Right? So that is
why the battle this war happened
according to mythological accounts
because of the three goddesses and so
on. But there could have been
geopolitical motives. Maybe Troy was
very wealthy. Maybe the Greeks wanted
the wealth. Maybe they wanted to control
the trade routes that Troy could control
from its geographical position. So maybe
there is that. But we are given a
mythological account because it's very
ancient history. Right? So Hector is
this great defender of the city of Troy,
wasn't he? And he is portrayed as this
great morally upright man because why?
Because he defends his city. He defends
his people. He also defends his family.
You know, historians and writers, they
admire his sense of duty, his sense of
self-sacrifice. He's defending Troy for
his loved ones, for his people despite
knowing that he faces overwhelming odds
and he is eventually slain by Achilles.
So, so
Hector, he embodies great virtues,
loyalty, bravery, uh self-sacrifice,
etc. And Achilles, the Greek, he why why
is he fighting? He hasn't come to fight
for his family, right? He's fighting for
personal glory. is fighting for
expansion for for Greek expansionism for
Greek conquest, right? Um he he's a very
proud man. He has this this this you
could say sin from an Abrahamic
perspective, Christian perspective. The
pride of sin, the sin of the sin of
pride. He's also short-tempered,
hot-headed. He has rage. He has pride
and uh he seeks personal glory more than
Greek glory. He seeks personal glory.
Sometimes he is unfair. Sometimes he's
cool, right? He's egoistic. So, so
Achilles is all about individual
greatness, personal glory. He's he has
excessive pride. He is very
short-tempered. So, obviously if you
compare Hector and and and Achilles, you
would say that Hector is more morally
correct or a pride. But here's the
problem in in in viewing
for anal here's the problem in analyzing
historical events through the lens of
morality.
It you cannot bring morality and
emotions
into analyzing
what happened and why it happened and
who is right or who is wrong. See like I
say when I discuss geopolitics there is
no right or wrong in geopolitics. There
are winners and losers. Okay. And the
world of geopolitics is amoral. There is
no place for morality in geopolitics.
And what is history? What are historical
events? They are yesterday's
geopolitics.
Right? So when we study history we we
have to understand motivations.
We have to understand causality. We have
to understand actions and consequences
that is causality, cause and effect and
we have to understand the context of the
actions that that that were taken.
We can obviously
look at morality as well but that's not
the correct uh lens the the ideal lens
through which you study history. Uh you
don't you should not judge historical
figures based on morality because what
is morality? It is today's ethical
standards.
But this war happened 3,200 years ago
roughly. It's pretty certain that the
ethical standards would have been kind
of different at the time. We discussed
our history. The ashwame yagna. Yudish
did the ashamed yagna. The horse was cut
into pieces eventually and more than 300
animals were sacrificed. You may find it
horrifying but our ancestors did that.
So you see today's eth ethical standards
where Indians prioritize a hinsa and
vegetarianism they are different from
the ethical standards of our ancestors.
Right? So it is not
the it's not a good practice to to
analyze historical events and and and to
judge people through the lens of
morality.
You know it it can offer some
interesting insights from today's
perspective but it may distort the
realities of that era. It may distort
the realities of that society. That
society may would definitely have had
different a different set of moral you
know different set of morals and ethics.
It will oversimplify things if we apply
morality. So when we study history, we
look at facts, we look at actions, we
look at consequences, we look at cause
and effect, we try and understand uh the
context in which the actions happened.
And we stay away from moralizing and
judging people. And that's that's how we
should study history. But obviously it's
that's not the way it's always done. And
when when we when it comes to our itas,
the Ramayan and the Mabar, there's a lot
of morality because these are, you know,
these these great epics they kind of
teach us how we should live life right
they teach us what is right what is
wrong so that's in the Indian context
but it may not apply in the Greek
context or some other context so that's
why context is important so anyhow I
would say that on on you know if you add
up the merits and demerits of the
actions of the two people that you're
talking about hect and Achilles overall.
Probably Hector was a better person.
Maybe more moral from today's
perspective. But hey, there was a
different world. Maybe Achilles was the
guy and he he got the glory. He got the
victory. At the end of the day, that's
what matters in geopolitics and in
history because it shapes the the
outcome of history, the outcomes of
history, and it shapes the future.
Right. Next question.
Amisha says, "Why didn't ancient
Egyptian wall paintings depict ancient
Egyptians wearing winter clothing?
Although modern day Egypt can get pretty
cold in the winters?" That's a good
question. See, if you watch, if you take
a snapshot from the past 300 and three
Ask Kabijit episodes, you will see me
wearing a variety of different kinds of
clothes. Sometimes I'm wearing something
really warm, right? Sometimes I'm
wearing a t-shirt, sometimes I'm wearing
something else. So, you will see me
wearing all kinds of things. But when it
comes to Egyptian wall paintings,
Egyptian wall carvings,
you will you will see Egyptians wearing
pretty skimpy clothing, right? A
clothing that obviously is clearly is
suited to what? To to a summer kind of
climate. Why is that so? Because you're
right, Egypt can get pretty cold in the
winters. No question about that. So why
is it so? That's a great question.
Yep. This is how we should try to
understand history, analyze history. So
we have to understand this temple art
in Egypt. You know this wall paintings,
wall carvings, etc. Even the sculptures,
these are typically especially the
paintings and carvings. These are in
Egyptian temples and great Egyptian
monuments dedicated to royalty. Right?
So these so so this is ancient Egyptian
art that has survived. So this art was
idealized art. Its objective the
objective of this art was to show the
status
of the people who are depicted in the
art. It was
it its objective was to show the values
and religious context, religious
concepts of of Egyptian society.
That's the that was the purpose of this
art to show the status of the people who
are depicted and to showcase the values
and religious concepts of Egyptian
society. The high values and high
religious concepts of Egyptian society.
The objective of this art was not to
show daily realities. It was not to show
seasonal changes. Okay. So that's why
you will find this idealized depiction
of people. Um so people individuals with
usually kings, queens, etc. Pharaohs who
are depicted in this art and typically
also servants in attendance and warriors
etc. You will find them generally
wearing
simple attire,
attire that's elegant but simple. Uh you
will see that the people who are
depicted are generally young people. So
the art emphasizes youth vitality. It
emphasizes royal status or or whatever
status the people have. Right? Uh so
that was the purpose of the art. It
would not depict seasonal dress. It
would not show any it did not have
practical purpose. It is it has this
idealistic purpose and this art it was
designed it was meant to be timeless. It
was meant to be eternal. It was meant to
be ideal. Okay. Especially in in tombs
where royalty and other people were
buried. Um so in if you see the art that
is on the walls of tombs inside tombs
you will see that the it will generally
so show the the deceased people the dead
people enjoying a pleasant afterlife. So
in that you will show them young and and
vital and vigorous and happy and wearing
nice simple elegant clothing right they
will not be shown to be enduring the
discomforts of cold winters with with
heavy clothing. That's the deal. But but
there is a caveat.
Okay, let's go to our friend Google and
let us Google fume mummy art. Check this
out. So let's see this
fume
mummy portraits. So the so the uh
Egyptian wall paintings etc we're
talking about are the wall paintings
that are from before the Greek and Roman
periods in Egypt. Now let's talk about
the fume mummy portraits. So this is
from about 100 BC to about 300 AD. And
over here you will find these are also
Egyptian people but from the Roman and
Greek period, Greek and Roman period.
And you will find that these people are
are depicted wearing a variety of
different kinds of dresses. Typically
helenic or Roman style dresses. And some
of them have pretty heavy clothing.
Definitely very different from what you
will find in the pre uh Greek period
in uh Egypt. So if you see the five
mummies,
very interesting portraits, very
realistic, lifelike portraits, and these
people are depicted wearing different
kinds of dresses, including potentially
clothing you would wear in winter,
right? And uh reconstruction. Let's see.
Reconstruction.
So you can see what these people look
like because the originals are pretty
lifelike, right? Um,
as you can see, I mean, this lady could
still be walking around the streets of
Egypt
on this person, too. Uh, so that's the
deal. So, the five mummy portraits are
very different, and they do depict
potentially some Egyptian people in
potentially winter clothing. All right?
Because the context was different.
Shub 1405 says compare pre-Christian
Europe with Christian Europe in terms of
women's equality, presence of social
hierarchal system.
Okay,
pre-Christian Europe and Christian
Europe. So historically Europe was
polytheistic.
The people of Europe all across Europe
and all across Eurasia, India westwards
practiced different manifestations of
the same culture. the ancient
Indo-Uropean culture
which all came from one place whichever
that place is that's the RN invasion
myth right u and of all the different
manifestations of Indo-European culture
the oldest that we know of is the Vic
culture and it's obviously a
polytheistic culture and all these
different European you know parts of
Europe whether it's the Celtic regions
the plutonic regions uh the Slavic
regions the Nordic regions whatever they
all worshiped gods that essentially had
onetoone correspondences with the old
Vic gods. So it was polytheism
and what kind of society did you have in
Europe at this time and what was the
what was this the the role and status of
women in in pre-Christian Europe before
Christianity was imposed on Europe in
terms of women's equality and so on. So
first of all when we talk about equality
let's understand that equality is a
modern thing
before I say anything let me just make
it very clear I am in favor of equality
of genders okay everybody should have
the same rules and laws that apply to
them irrespective of what gender they
are there are two genders
is that controversial should not be
there are two genders male and female
and rules, laws, whatever should be
gender agnostic.
That's what I believe in. Everybody
should should should have the same rules
and laws applying to them irrespective
of the gender. I hope I make myself
clear. I am in favor of that. Now
understand this. Historically,
you did not have equality of genders.
You had gender roles.
males would perform a set of roles in
society and females would perform a
different set of roles in society.
That's how it was across the world
including in Europe.
So what
what kind of roles did women play in
pre-Christian Europe? It it depends on
the place. So for example in Celtic
societies for example
what is now called the UK
before the Romans invaded
um this place was entirely Celtic.
Celtic peoples in even if you look at
Spain or Western France you had Celtic
people there even Switzerland right all
Celtic peoples and cultures. So in
Celtic culture there was the practice of
matrioity.
When a man married a woman he would move
from his birthplace or wherever he lived
to where the woman's household was.
So what does that indicate? It indicates
that women controlled property
and that's the kind of role they played.
So women had property, they had property
rights, they controlled property. And
men were supposed to move to the woman's
house, not the other way around. But
these were not matriarchal societies.
You had met locality but not matriarchy.
These were still patriarchal societies.
Yeah, that's how it was. Um generally
women um
they
had significant legal rights. They had
the right to their dowy. So you had the
practice of dowry. When a girl got
married, her family would give. So even
when you where you did not have matri
localality where the girl would go to
the husband's household uh her parents
would give her some gifts, right? That
was called the dowy to start off the new
life. And even after marriage, the woman
had rights to her dowy. So it was still
her property, not the husband's
property. And she also did not become
the husband's property. women um they
held a high position in society as
teachers, as healers, right? That was
common ac across various pre-Christian
European societies.
Um
yeah, so that's the kind of status women
had in pre-Christian society. It was a
pretty uh you know pretty high status
that women had. Um then you had the
introduction of Christianity into
Europe. starts with emperor Constantine
of Byzantium and he has the council of
Nika in present day roughly Turkey and
they amend the the the the text of
Christianity to some extent and
Constantine makes Christianity the
official religion state religion of the
of the Roman Empire and eventually
Christianity overruns Europe over the
next 6 700 years and it is imposed on
the people of Europe generally by force
through pretty brutal force
right and then you have the dark ages in
Europe the medieval era, the dark ages
era of Europe. Uh so the position of
women and status of women in society
changes drastically once Christianity is
imposed. What happens? So
the church it portrayed women
as spiritually weak.
It portrayed women as intellectually
inferior to men. It portrayed women as
the root cause of sin and it portrayed
women as being prone to sin, more prone
to sin than men because of this concept
called original sin. Right? So women
were were were portrayed as temptresses,
dangerous temptresses who required who
needed male control. Okay? And this was
done to justify the subordination, the
legal subordination and subjugation of
women. It was used to justify the
exclusion of women from positions of
authority.
Okay. In in the past, women could have
very high positions in society before
Christianity was imposed. But once
Christianity was imposed, women became
secondass citizens in society. There was
this legal principle that said that
husband and wife are the same person
and that person is the husband.
Okay? [laughter]
And then you had the witch hunts. So see
Christianity was all all about control.
We'll discuss the witch hunts. So what
was the uh structure of society during
the Christian age in Europe? It was a
rigid society. It was a hierarchal
pyramidical society. religiously
sanctioned hierarchal pyramid. At the
very top was a very small percentage of
the population. The clergy,
okay, those who pray.
Even in the clergy, you had a pyramidal
structure, a military top- down command
and control structure. At the top, we
had the pope, then you had bishops, then
you had priests, then you had monks, and
you had nuns. And all these people even
though they they they had different
levels of status and power they were the
most powerful uh you know tip of the
pyramid of society. Um the church owned
huge amounts of land. It collected 10%
tax from society. It's called the tithe
and it it exercised enormous political
influence. So that is the tip of the
iceberg. Okay. The the clergy. Below the
clergy in European society, you had the
nobility, the the ones who ought. Okay,
it was kings and then you had the lords
and baronss and dukes and knights. These
people they controlled the land that the
church did not control and they also
collected taxes and they did military
service and they fought wars and they
they exercised the
judicial authority. They decided laws
that that were different from church
laws, you know, secular laws or whatever
you want to call that, right? So below
the clergy, you have the nobility,
including the king and everybody else.
Then you have the peasants.
So the peasants are about 90% of the
population. And among the peasants, you
have essentially slaves who are called
the surfs or the villains who were bound
to the land. They were part of the land.
They could not leave the land. and they
were required to work on the fields of
their lord. They were forbidden from
leaving without the lord's permission
which would never be given. So they were
essentially owned by the land owner, the
serfs. They were essentially slaves. And
you had a small number of people called
the free peasants who had a little more
rights and liberties but uh they also
could not uh survive without giving
service to various lords. So this is all
the structure of the society and you can
see there's no women included in this
right all the people with any kind of
power are men. Um and that's how it was.
So this feudal this is called the feudal
system and it it created this web of
obligations in society based on who owns
how much land and who is part of which
part of the pyramid and each person owed
allegiance to those above them in the
pyramid. a rigidly hierarchal cast
system.
What did the church teach? It taught you
if you were European
that your social position was decided at
birth. It is the God it is the Christian
God who decided your position in life in
society. Your position in society was
divinely ordained.
Social mobility was impossible. Don't
even dream of it. If you dream of social
mobility, you're questioning the will of
the go of God, not the gods. You're
questioning the will of God. Right? So
this is very different from
pre-Christian societies in which you had
a lot of social mobility and women were
respected members of society. Right? So
that's how it was. Your your birth
determined your station. Uh social
mobility was impossible. It was it was
essentially heresy to even think of
social mobility. So the church had this
enormous control and power over the
entire population of Europe. Okay? Uh it
was the biggest land owner in Europe.
I'll tell you what
in 21st century India the largest
non-government land owner in India is
the church.
I kid you not. Right. So that's how it
was. That is the difference between
pre-Christian Europe and post-Christian
and Christian Europe. In Christian
Europe, women were secondass citizens.
They they essentially had no rights.
They had no rights. And
how did I mean have things changed?
Yeah, obviously things have changed
today. Today Europe is the the defender
I mean the west is the defender of human
rights and freedoms and equality and all
that. But let me tell you a small little
tidbit of information. There is a nation
called Switzerland. Beautiful nation,
fantastic nation. Okay.
So in India we have states in the US we
have states right? Utah, Wisconsin,
Oregon and so on. In India we have
states like Gujarat um Maharashtra Assam
Telangana
um Hana and so on. In Switzerland you
don't have states you have cantons.
Those are the divisions stateike
divisions within Switzerland.
Switzerland itself is pretty small. So
the last Swiss canton
to grant women the right to vote
was Appenzel inter in inner ruden
appelen inner ruden.
It gave women the right to vote in 1990.
Until 1990 in the Swiss canton of Aenzel
inner ruden women did not have the right
to vote. And the first time women
actually participated in elections by
voting was in 1991.
Is this good? Is this bad? It's none of
my business. It's an internal matter of
Switzerland. They have the right to live
whichever way they want. Others should
stay out of it. Similarly, others should
stay out of India as well. But that
doesn't happen, doesn't it? Anyhow,
that's the deal. So that's the
difference between the rights of women
and the status of women in society.
Before Christianity was imposed upon
Europe and after Christianity was
imposed upon Europe, it was disastrous
for for women. And u because women had
such high positions and and rules in
society like healers and teachers that's
why it was very important to to destroy
that that right in those rights and that
status of women for the church to
exercise complete control over society
and they did this by publishing a book
called the Malus Malfearum which was the
which was a bestseller in Europe for
centuries and what does malus
maleficarum mean? It means the hammer of
the witches. It was a manual on how to
identify
women who are witches,
what tests to perform upon them to prove
that they are witches, and uh how to
punish them for being witches. So, one
of the ways to test whether a woman was
a witch was to tie heavy rocks to her to
her feet or legs and put her in deep
water.
So if she floats despite all of that
then she's a witch because it's magic.
That's how you identify a witch. And if
she drowns then she was not a witch. How
nice.
Heads I win tells you tells you you
lose. And then if you identify a woman
as a witch then you have to obviously
burn her alive after doing a tremendous
amount of brutal torture and stuff. Uh
so mostly women will be burned. I think
millions of women were burned alive. But
today, um, academics will tell you only
20, 30,000 were burned alive. In the
1980s, until the 1980s, 1990s, everyone
knew that millions of women were burned
alive as witches. But today, there's
been academic revisionism. And now it's
only maybe 10, 20,000. That's what they
say today. That's how you revise
history, don't you? Uh, so women used to
be burnt alive, millions of them as
witches. And if you did not burn her
alive, there were other ways of killing
them. There was something called
pressing to death. So you would place a
woman
on on on a hard surface like rock and
you would place heavy rocks on her chest
and other parts of the body and you will
break the arms and legs first and then
the rib cage and eventually she will
suffocate to death pressing to death.
Yeah. They had many nice charming ways
of of of
punishing evil women who were consorts
of Satan or whatever. Yeah. So that's
what happened post Christianity, post
the the the imposition of Christianity
on the people of Europe.
Right. Okay.
Next question. Amisha says, "How were
Jews treated during the American Civil
War? Was anti-semitism ever an issue
throughout the conflict?" Well, let's
discuss the position of Jews in the
United States overall.
So there was this um there was this guy
who was born in Boston, Massachusetts
in the 17th
century
1600 something. Okay. He was born in
Boston. His name was Eliu Elhu Yale.
Elihu Yale. He was Jewish. He was born
in Boston, but he lived in in the US,
present day US only as a child. He spent
the rest of his life in England and in
India.
He became an official, a high-ranking
official of the East India Company and
as such he plundered a tremendous amount
of wealth out of our
our land, our people, out of India. And
in 1718,
he donated some money and some other
stuff to someone who wanted to start a
school or college in the United States.
And because Ilhu Yale was so generous in
his donation, the person who founded
that college, they named it Yale
College. Today it is called Yale
University. One of the most highly
sought after IV league universities in
the US. It was built from a seed funding
of money plundered from India. That is
Eluiel who was Jewish. I am just stating
facts here. It has nothing to do with
his religion by the way. I'm just saying
that Jews had a high position in
American society right in the 17th and
18th centuries. Uh but anti-semitism was
definitely present in the US in
different forms, shapes and forms. Um
it it it had various ways of expressing
itself. It had different in intensities
depending on the place and the time. The
civil war era was is a very small era.
Let's discuss a slightly broader era
from the 1700s all the way to second
world war around that that period that
gives us enough space to to discuss this
in some length. So
so Jews especially those who were
wealthy had had
high level of acceptance in American
society. there was a synagogue that that
operated in Charleston in the 19th
century and u that that was allowed and
nobody had an issue with that. So if you
were Jewish and you were wealthy and you
assimilated more or less then there was
no issue for you in in some parts or
maybe many parts of the US um in the
south see when we talk about the civil
war in the US we're talking about north
versus south the north eventually won
north is Abraham Lincoln and south is
the ones who attempted to secede and
partition the country so the south was
in favor of of of slavery the north
wanted to end slavery because of
different economic models For the south
it made sense to continue slavery
because it economically was it made
sense for them. So in the south you had
Jews who adopted who had assimilated
into the local society. They adopted
local customs and they held prominent
positions right. Some of them were
plantation owners. Some of them were
slave owners. Uh Judah P. Benjamin in
Louisiana who was a highranking official
in the confederate government. He was a
plantation owner slave owner. he was
Jewish. So you can see that Jews had
prominent positions in the south as well
as the north. Uh during the civil war
you had Jews fighting on both sides and
generally there was not much
anti-semitism during the civil war. Um
there was this general right Ulysus
Srant who issued an order during the
civil war um expelling all the all Jews
from his military district. um it is in
what Tennessee, Mississippi, Kentucky,
that area. And he claimed that Jews were
responsible for illegal trading of
whatever that sort of thing. But um so
Ulysus Srant issued this order expelling
Jews, but Abraham Lincoln reversed that.
So there was some anti-semitism, but
Abraham Lincoln was not anti-semitic.
You see? Um
and then after the civil war you you you
had Jews who would occasionally be
excluded from various social clubs and
resorts, sometimes even from
universities and they could potentially
at times depending on the time and place
[clears throat] encounter discrimination
u in in in housing for example maybe
professional discrimination. Um
sometimes Jews were excluded from some
um hotels, from some clubs, from some
residential uh developments, you know,
that sort of thing would happen
sometimes. Um and
in the leadup to sec to the second world
war, anti-semitic attitudes became more
pronounced for a while in the United
States. Henry Ford
was kind of an anti-semite. Okay.
Um, and you had this organization called
the Klux Clan. Klux Clan in the US,
which was primarily a racist
organization. They had this great hate
for African-Americans.
Uh, they also targeted Catholics, but
they also occasionally
targeted Jews as well. Uh, so that was
there.
So, in the run-up to the Second World
War, you had more anti-semitism. And
then I suppose later it it became less
pronounced. So that's that's been a
feature of western society.
Anti-semitism. Uh Jews have been
persecuted for 2,000 plus years in
Europe. They have faced all kinds of
discrimination. They have faced
massacres. They've faced all kinds of
allegations of so-called what? Blood
liel or whatever. They've been accused
of poisoning wells and all kinds of
conspiracies been spread against them.
uh there have been massacres of Jews in
in in England, in other parts of Europe
and so on. So the Jews they
they it's not something new for them
this sort of uh treatment and they've
also faced some of that in the United
States probably less than what they
faced in Europe. So overall that's how
Jews were treated in the United States
not during the civil war but from the
1700s all the way to the second world
war period. And uh yeah today Jews
obviously have a better position much
better position in society and Israel is
is kind of a favored nation of the US
today. So things have changed.
Napoleon Singh Shikhawat says what was
the objective of Nazi Germany during the
North African campaign and did win Romel
really want to assassinate the painter
Adolf Hitler? Let us go to the map.
Nazi Germany
the the North Africa campaign right okay
let us go to the map and let us discuss
the North Africa campaign in brief
right so we are discussing North Africa
how does it all start it starts around
1940 roughly roughly give or take a few
months or years okay you you can check
up the exact dates so it starts with the
Italians
u invading Libya and they wanted to go
further east and capture Egypt and
potentially even go all the way to
Ethiopia because the Italians in have an
old history in Ethiopia going back to
the first world war. So the Italians
they land in Tripoli and then they make
a move on Egypt and then they are beaten
back very badly. It was a disaster for
Italy. But then the Germans they decide
to to move in and support the Italians.
Now before we discuss the North African
campaign, why did Germany get involved
in this? Why they they were fighting the
Europeans, right? They were fighting
England. Why did they have to make a
move on North Africa? Well, there are
good reasons for that. See, North if you
control if Italy is your ally and you
control France and Greece and then you
also control let's say North Africa,
then you control the entire
Mediterranean region.
And if you can make a move on Egypt and
control the Suez Canal, that is disaster
for England, for the UK, right? And if
you can take over, let's say, the West
Asia region, then that cuts off what
what the UK needs the most, which is
energy, oil. So that makes sense. It it
makes a lot of sense for Germany to if
possible take over North Africa, take
over West Asia, take over the Suez
Canal, control the Mediterranean and
deny the UK the oil that it so
desperately needs. So that was the
objective of Nazi Germany. So Roel makes
a move in support of of the Italians. He
also lands in the Tripoli region and for
a while he has great success and uh he
he makes a move into Egypt and he fights
a few battles and he wins those battles
and uh his campaign is going great but
then the British under what was his name
was it Montgomery with somebody else so
they then start a counterattack
and it's sometime in 1942 or 43 or
wherever it was that eventually uh the
North African campaign was of Nazi
Germany was derailed and defeated. So
that is in very brief what I'm telling
you but obviously it took several years
for this whole thing to to happen. Um
and Romel was a brilliant general. He
was called the desert fox if I'm not
mistaken. And he is considered to have
been a great very ethical fighter. He
was not known for cruelty or you know he
was known as an ethical person. He
fought war. He he did fight a war but he
fought it along apparently ethical
grounds.
Now um in 1944 there was this uh plot to
assassinate Adul Khla
and some of the people involved in the
plot were kind of associated in the past
with Irwin Romel
that's why the finger of suspicion and
potentially blame fell on Irwin Romel so
he was uh by the time he was back in
Germany and he was then given a choice
commit suicide head.
If you do that, then your family will
not be touched and you will you will be
given an honorable funeral and all that.
Nobody will be told that you you were
allegedly part of a plot. If you don't
do that, then not only will you be
executed, but your family will will
suffer consequences. So, Urvin Romel
decided to do it himself. And that was
the end of Romel. Did he really want to
assassinate Adolf Hitler? He probably
did not want to do that. He may have
wanted to remove Hitler from power but
not assassinate him. So even that is a
matter of conjecture whether he wanted
to remove Hitler from power but he was
definitely not part of the assass
assassination plot. But when an
assassination plot happens paranoia
rises and if you're Hitler you want to
take out anybody who could potentially
have even a small chance of being
associated with the plot. That's why
Irwin Raml well he met his um
unfortunate fate
right
Amisha says why is D-Day remembered as
being such a pivotal moment within the
second world war what does the D in DDay
stand for what does the D stand for it's
as far as I know it only stands for day
so there is something called H hour
which is the hour at which a military
operation will start in that H al also
means hour
So [clears throat] D-Day meant as far as
I know D meant day. I don't think it
meant decision day or any any such
thing. I it just meant day. Now why is
it remembered as being such a pivotal
moment
uh within the second world war? because
it is it it
it's where the west
which is um the UK as well as the US
they made a landing in Normandy
in western France the coasts on the
beaches of Normandy they were able to
establish a tow hold in Normandy and
then they were able to step by step
liberate France and and and make a move
on Germany itself so at This time
Germany had bit off more than it could
chew. It was fighting the USSR. It was
fighting the UK. It had
Yeah. It it had it was occupied on so
many different fronts. North Africa
also, right?
And the USSR was putting up a huge
amount of resistance. It was slowly
clawing back the territory the Germans
had taken. It was beating Germany back.
And then the Germany have to divert
resources to fight off the Americans and
and the British who have landed in
Normandy are taking back France. So
Germany was forced to divide its its
forces and it this eventually led to the
defeat of Nazi Germany. So that's why
the tide turns when the Americans and
the British
launched this invasion of Normandy.
That's where the tide turned and much
most of the fighting and winning was
done by the Soviets.
But in popular depictions, it is the
Americans who win the day. So that's why
D-Day is such a pivotal moment because
that is where the tide of the war
actually turned. [clears throat]
Nirvana Shank says, "Why did the Western
Roman Empire fall in the fifth century
CE AD despite maintaining advanced
technology, infrastructure, and a large
military for centuries? Whereas the
Eastern Roman or Byzantine Empire
survived for nearly a millennium under
similar pressures,
right? Well, there are several reasons.
You may have the best military. You may
have uh tremendous amount of of land.
You may have tremendous wealth. But if
your leadership
is weak, none of that matters.
leadership makes as well as breaks
empires.
Over time,
the Western Roman Empire, which was
based out of Rome, its leadership became
increasingly
indulgent in in luxury. It became
increasingly corrupt. It became in
increasingly inefficient.
There were internal power struggles.
There was corruption. There was
politics. there was there was
degeneracy let's say right and when it
comes to the Byzantine Empire they had
less of that they also had geographical
advantages that the western Roman Empire
did not have so the western Roman Empire
it had no natural defenses it had the Ry
river it had the Danube river if you
cross that you could come and invade
Rome [clears throat] the Roman Empire
and you had they had multiple waves of
invasions
by the by the visigoths, by the vandals,
uh the Huns, Atilad Hun and so much more
happened. Wave after wave of invasion at
times even Rome fell to these invasions.
Um so they did not have great natural
defenses
and uh
and a lot of the population was
concentrated in cities with because
that's where the wealth was and there
was a tremendous amount of inequality in
society. uh
the wealthy people they would bring in
slaves to work on the farms and uh
because of that the wealth was
concentrated it's in in the hand in the
hands of some people a small number of
people there was a lot of poverty as
well but overall the empire was very
very rich very wealthy and then you had
emperors like Ilabaloo
what did I just say let me show you
let's go to Googlealoo
Let's let's Google this guy.
There we have it. Let us see what
Wikipedia has to say about this
fantastic person.
So he ruled he lived between 204 and 222
AD. So he died around the age of 18. But
he was a Roman emperor. Okay. Um his
short reign was notorious for religious
controversy and alleged sexual
debauchery.
Um let's see what what do we what can we
find about this gentleman. So he was
assassinated at the age of 18. Okay. And
he was replaced by his cousin.
Um
he had this reputation for extreme
eccentricity, decad decadence, zelry and
sexual promiscuity.
One of the worst reputations among Roman
emperors. He abandoned himself to the
grossest pleasures with ungoverned fury.
Um, Elagabalos had nothing at all to
make up for his vices which are of such
a kind that it is too disgusting to even
allude to them. [laughter]
He was not a tyrant. He was incompetent.
Probably the least able emperor Rome has
ever had.
Um, and
modern historians, some of them will
describe him as a tragic enigma lost
behind centuries of prejudice. [snorts]
Uh, let's see.
>> [laughter]
>> what what we can see about this this
fine gentleman.
Um
he married a vestal virgin who was not
supposed to marry, right? A flagrant
breach of Roman law and tradition
which held that any vestal virgin found
to have engaged in sexual intercourse
was to be buried alive. Uh that sort of
thing. Okay, nice. What else? Um
six horse chariot and so on. Uh he had
how many wives? First wife was Julia
Cornelia Pa. Then he had the vested
virgin Julia Aquilia Sea as a second
wife. He divorced her then took a third
wife was Ana Aurelia Fina.
Um then he divorced Ana Fina and
remarried Aquilinia Sea. Then this
emperor Elagabalos was the had a husband
who was Hierocles an exslave and chariot
driver and he also married a man called
Zoticus who was an athlete
and this emperor he prostituted himself
in taverns and brothel.
He may have identified as female. He may
have been transgender. He may have
sought sex reassignment surgery.
um he wore makeup and wigs. He preferred
to be called a lady and not a lord and
so much more. Okay, so that's the kind
of people who were ruling Rome. He was
the worst. He was the worst. And
eventually he was assassinated by his
own guards uh to no one's great
surprise, I suppose. Yeah.
And then you had other emperors who were
you know not that
out of the way but uh who were pretty
incompetent and and eventually you know
the western Roman Empire just fell by
the fifth century uh AD. Uh when it
comes to the Byzantine Empire, the
Eastern Roman Empire, their emperors
were more competent. U they had more
professional standing armies. Uh they
were able to fight off their adversaries
much better. They were better organized,
better administered. They did not have
all the weirdness that that western Rome
had. And you know, so because of these
factors, the Byzantine Empire was able
to survive until what 14
which when you know the 15th century
when the Turks took over.
Rahul Dunak says in spite of forming 25
million years ago, why hasn't the lake
Bal turned salty? Why does it remain a
freshwater lake? Great question. Let us
go to the maps and we shall discover
what is the deal with this lake. Lake
Bal. Where is this lake? It's in Rasha
is Rasha. Yes. So where is this lake?
It's the It's a huge lake. It's north of
Mongolia. This is Lake Bal. It holds
about 20% of the surface fresh water of
our planet. Huge lake. If you just
roughly measure the distance from tip to
tip, it's about six it's over 600
kilometers,
right? It's a it's a massive lake about
20% of the surface fresh water of the
planet and and it's its greatest depth
is more than one and a half kilometers.
So it's pretty deep. So this lake it
formed about 20 30 35 million years
before today. How did this lake form? It
formed because of tectonic events
because of the formation of a rift
valley in this region where you have two
tectonic plates moving apart. So a
valley forms a rift valley and over
millions of years it filled up with
water which is supplied to it by
hundreds of rivers maybe not hundreds of
rivers maybe dozens of rivers. It's got
all these little rivers that bring in
this fresh water and it has I think only
one river the angora river or angara
river which carries water out. So there
is no sea near this river and uh there
is no connection between this river and
any ocean which is salt water and all
the water that comes into the river is
is produced by melting snows and ice
glacial melt water mostly which is why
it remains fresh water there's no salt
amazing beautiful so that's the reason
why this lake has not turned salty
that's why it remains a freshwater lake
What about a different lake? If you go
to northern India, if you go to Ladak,
we have this lake over here. It's called
Pangong, Lake Pangong. And if you go to
this lake and you taste the water, it is
salty water. So why is the Pangong lake
a saltwater lake even though it's high
in the Himalayas
and even though Lake Bal is a freshwater
lake? Why is Pangong a saltwater lake?
This one here, it's a beautiful location
by the way, Lake Pangong in Ladak. So
the deal is this. Let's zoom out.
So the Indian subcontinent was once
attached to Africa.
It was once attached to Africa and
Madagascar and because of tectonic
activity, the Indian subcontinent
launched was launched by tectonic forces
across the Indian Ocean. It was
somewhere overong
about 66 million years ago when you had
the deck and traps traps volcanism in
India and about 30 40 50 million years
before today the subcontinent slammed
into Eurasia and it is still slamming
into urasia
and this collision happened with such
incredible force that it threw up these
gigantic mountains called the Himalayas
which are still rising. So just before
the Indian subcontinent slams into
Eurasia, there was
an ocean between India and Eurasia which
was called the Tethus ocean. And when
the Indian subcontinent slammed into
Eurasia, some of that water remained
trapped between the subcontinent and
Eurasia and that formed all these
Himalayan lakes and that's why Pangong
Lake is still salty because it still
retains the salt of that ancient ocean
and it has no rivers that take the water
out and it has no rivers that bring
fresh water in. Right? That's why it
remains salty. Whatever water comes into
the Pangong lake comes as a as a
consequence of precipitation either rain
or snow and whatever water goes out goes
out because of evaporation. There's no
other means of the water going out.
That's why Pangong Lake is salty. What
about these two lakes here?
Right,
we have Manserov
and Rakasal. One second. Is is this the
location? It's obviously
no somewhere else. Let me see. Manover
Monser over Lake.
Okay, where is it? It's over here. Okay,
so today if you look at the map it will
say some weird Chinese names which is
because we have allowed China to to
capture and occupy Tibet. So when it
comes to the lake manserver which is the
large lake on the right of the screen
that is a freshwater lake but right next
to it we have Rakastal
which is a salty lake right so it's a
big conundrum as to how this has
happened because see manser over it it
has some some little rivlets that come
into it and give it fresh water
and somehow
it has been able able to you know get
rid of its of its salt content but
Rajasthal has not been able to do that.
So it's it's one of the great mysteries.
How come one lake is fresh water, the
other one is brackish or saline? And I'm
sure there's a good geological
explanation for that, but I am not sure
what it is. I've not looked into it. So
anyhow, that's that's a bit about the
geological history of the of the planet.
Right. Next question.
Napoleon Singh Shikawad says, "I watched
a video of yours in which you were
talking about Yamna people being from
the Indian subcontinent, but as I looked
into it more into it, the internet
showed me only three Yamna men being
brown skinned, the rest of them had
white skin with blonde hair and blue
eyes." Why is that? Please enlighten.
So, let's let's uh go and replicate the
experiment that Napoleon Shing Shikhawat
has done. Okay, let's see. Google. Oh,
here we have it. Yum. Yeah. People,
let's see what these people look like.
Let's see images of these people. Um,
so if you look here, you will see this
Yamna gentleman looks brown skinned,
dark hair, dark eyes, looks like an
Indian. This gentleman looks once again
like an Indian. And this gentleman looks
very very Indian. Standard brown skin,
brown eyes, dark hair, right? But then
you will see you will see this this
person is depicted as a European you
know light colored hair blondish hair.
Then you will see this gentleman
and you will see other depictions of
Yamna people who are depicted as kind of
European. Let's see what other
depictions we have. So these are all
artistic reconstructions based on the
skulls.
Okay. So you can depict them whichever
way you want. If you are an artist, you
can depict them as a European person.
You can depict them with whatever skin
color, hair color, and eye color you
want. So, here is one example of a
red-haired Yamna with white skin and
blue eyes. It's an artistic
representation.
This gentleman has blue eyes and blonde
hair and beard.
So, the artist decides how to represent
the person, right? I mean you could take
me and you could do an artistic
representation of me with blue eyes and
blonde hair and white skin in that case
I would look kind of European I suppose
right so that's what's been done here
now let's go to okay let's check
Wikipedia what it has to say okay and
why did I say that see I do not say that
yamnas were from Indian subcontinent I
said that yamnas
may have been from the subcontinent
maybe and they definitely were not white
people is what I said so why did I say
that Let's see what Wikipedia has to say
about their skin color. Okay,
skin.
So based on genetic analysis. Okay,
first of all, Wikipedia is not
necessarily a reliable source of
information, but let's for the sake of
time see what Wikipedia has to say. So
there are some genetic studies that are
referenced over here. People of the
Yamna culture are believed to have had
mostly brown eye color, light to
intermediate skin, and brown hair color
with some variation. Okay, let's see
some more.
A 2022 study by Lazaridis Aal found that
the typical phenotype among the Yamna
population was brown eyes, brown hair in
intermediate skin color. None of their
Yamna s samples were predicted to have
either blue eyes or blonde hair in
contrast with later step groups which
are not Yamna in in Russia and Central
Asia. Right?
So the Yamna people were a single
genetically coherent group and who were
responsible for spreading Indo-Uropean
languages. That is complete conjecture.
You can't prove or disprove that. That's
nonsense. That's what David Reich says.
I I mean that is pure conjecture. But
the point is none of them had blue eyes
or blonde hair. They had intermediate
skin color. What do we mean by
intermediate skin color?
white black intermediate it's somewhere
between white and black that is
intermediate okay let's say we have no
black people in Eurasia so then it means
that it's intermediate between white and
brown it means light brown that is what
the skin color of the yamna people was
light brown not dark brown not white
light brown
okay and they had brown eyes and dark
hair brown or black hair maybe brown
hair you'll see plenty of such people in
northern and western India maybe even
southern India you'll find people like
that many so that's the whole point okay
an artist can make any kind of depiction
of a person based on their skull
structure but that's an artist's
decision if an artist has a certain bias
he he prefers you know the European
origin theory of the of the arian race
so-called then he will paint the amna
white with blue eyes and blonde hair but
what Does the genetic evidence tell us
they had light brown they they had light
brown skin, brown eyes and dark colored
hair. That is the deal. That's what we
know. All right. Okay.
Right.
Next question. Shub says what are the
origins of Rajputs and how did they
adopt Chhatria Dharma? And Ellesian says
are Jadav Rajputs in Maharashtra and
Jadon Yal of the same. Same with Chawans
and Chavan, Chri and Chowri, Raur and
Rord, Shindar Rajput and Cindia, Panoar,
Pawar and Maharashtra. Please answer. I
am Jadav Rajput. My ancestors came to
Maharashtra 400 years ago from Matura
Rowi Bayana. Okay. What is the origin?
What are the origins of the so-called
Rajputs?
First of all, we have discussed this in
the past, but this term Rajput did not
emerge until the middle until the last 5
600 years.
That's when the term Rajput appears in
historioggraphy in written history and
this term comes from the it means
Rajautra the son of sons of kings which
means people who had royal ancestry
right but in 1000 AD nobody called
themselves Rajputs
in 1200 AD most likely no one called
themselves Rajuts even though they are
now called Rajputs the Chawans or
whoever else right whoever else there
are so many of these These are not so
many a number of Rajput clans lineages.
So what's the origin of Rajput? So if
you if you read what the British and
Europeans wrote about Rajputs, they will
say that the Rajputs were of foreign
origin. They were either descendants of
skitians, Indoskit, but the skitians
themselves were of Indian ancestry by
the way. Anyhow,
either descendants of schizians or
descendants of Huns who knows,
[clears throat] right? White Aunwah
maybe that maybe something else. So
maybe foreign origin. But what does our
own history say?
These kingdoms which are now called
Rajput kingdoms they emerged in the
aftermath of the breakup and
disintegration and decline and
disintegration of the Gupta Empire.
So after the Guta Empire which encompass
the whole of the subcontinent
essentially it declines and and breaks
up then you have these independent
kingdoms that pop up and they eventually
eventually come to be known as the
Rajapur. But what were their origins?
So the origins it is said it is said
that there were 36 royal clans in India
royal royal lineages in India that come
back that date all the way to the
Mahajanapadas but that is the late Vic
times.
And those become the eventual uh
Rajputic lineages, Rajput lineages. So
you have different ancestors, right?
Surya, the solar dynasty and their
descendants, various Rajput lineages,
Chundraanch, Chundraanchi dynasties, the
dynasty, the lunar dynasty and their
descendant lineages which are different.
And then there is Agnikul which have
come from the fire from fire that sort
of thing.
So there are supposed to to be 36 royal
lineages in India. Let's see. And the
English historian James Todd wrote about
this. Let's let's go to Google and find
out what did James Todd write about
this. So James Todd 36 royal
races of India right what's it say?
Royal races. James Todd was this writer.
Um let's see what this has to say. I'm
sure it will have some kind of um list
that James Todd gave and James Todd
himself did not you know create the list
he simply copied it from from older uh
records.
So if we look at this
you are asking about the Jadav Rajputs
right? So this is a catalog of the 36
royal races of India which
most likely
originate in the late Vic time period.
And you you have something called Yadu
over here. As you can see there is this
one one lineage is called Yadu which
could be the originators of the Jadav
Rajputs of Maharash Maharashtra.
Does it have any other Yadu Jadav thing
over here? Joa
and Jet Jetwa Jala that's fine. Uh Jit
and okay so it looks like there's only
one Yadu Yadu apparently. So it looks
like the Yadu Rajuts are could be
related to the Jadav Rajputs in
Maharashtra. I'm not sure about Yadav
and Jadon and all that. I am not sure
about that. Can't say for sure.
And see when you say chawans and chavan
chri with a u and chi with a w that's
just English spellings that those
English spellings can differ that
doesn't matter. Ratur and rahor d it's
the same thing it's different ways of
writing the same thing. Uh shindai and
cindia the British called them cindias
they were actually shindi I'm not sure
if they were rajuts if they were part of
the 36 lineages but they were marata
warriors right
that sort of thing. So I'm not sure
about the Jadav. There is a Yadu uh
lineage that was listed in James Todd's
list. Is that related to the Jadavs of
Maharashtra? I am not sure about that.
Possibly it could be maybe it may not
be. I'm not sure. I am not an expert in
this matter. I only know about a few of
these lineages not all of them.
But that's about the origins of the
Rajput. How did they adopt Chhatria
Dharma? They were chhatrias, right? They
were warriors from the from the very
beginning. They did not decide one day
that okay now from today we will adopt
Dharma. Not like that. It was their way
of life. They were warriors. That was
their rule in society.
Okay. Um we have so many other questions
but we have crossed ours.
Let's take one more question from the
comments and I'll take take some from
the live chat. So
colorful mix says would you like to tell
me about Indian classical music?
Classical music was not just
entertainment for culture like India and
China. I'd like to know about the
science and philosophy surrounding our
classical music. How it came to be and
its role in healing and meditation.
Indian classical music Indian classical
Indian music overall it's the oldest
musical tradition in the world that we
know of. It dates back thousands of
years and it is based on something
called the ragas. And you know what is a
raga? Well, I don't have my guitar with
me otherwise I would have demonstrated
that. I've done that in the past. But a
raa is see in western in western music
you have scales. Scales is is a set of
notes cdc.
These are the seven notes of the
standard scale of the pentatonic scale.
uh the the major notes right um so the
western system it comes from India
because the system of raas with those
seven notes it predates Europe by
thousands of years it predates Greece by
thousands of years so we have scales in
western music it could be heptatonic
scales seven notes it could be hexatonic
scales with six notes it could be
pentatonic scales with five notes that
sort of thing
in Indian music we also have scales but
we more than scales we have raas what is
a raa we have you know there are I don't
know hundreds of raas you could create
and there's a ragas are classified into
something called thoughts and this
classification was done roughly 100 plus
years ago by by a gentleman called
bakande so we have ragas classified as
morning ragas evening ragas night ragas
afternoon ragas we have something called
raga bilaval which is a thought it's a
classification of ragas. Bilawal it's a
it's an Indian name not a Pakistani name
it's a morning raa then we have raa
kalyan which is an evening raga we have
raa kamage which is a night raa we have
raa marva which is a thought which is a
dusk raga very very yeah different kind
of so each raa it evokes
a mood an emotion
and based on the emotion you classify it
as and and and the rasa of the raa which
the emotion it it it evokes. You can
classify a raga as a morning raga or
evening raga, night raga, afternoon raga
or a seasonal raga like malahar which is
monsoon and uh you have ragavasant which
is springtime that sort of thing right.
So uh that is what ragas are like and uh
I suppose this form of music this this
classification of music emerged in the
well [clears throat]
at the very beginning of Indian
civilization over time it evolved over
time over centuries or thousands of
years that's why it is so complex and
it's the greatest system of music that
you have anywhere on the planet but it's
dying a slow death in India because
everyone's enamored with Bollywood music
and western music today but the Latest
system of music is Indian Indian
classical music. So Raa I'll tell you
what Raa is. I told you it it it has a
time morning, night, evening, afternoon
whatever it could have a season based on
the emotions it evokes.
A raa its structure its note structure
it has an ascending scale and a
descending scale. So a set of notes when
you are going from lower frequencies to
higher frequencies and a set of notes
which when you're descending from lower
higher frequencies to lower frequencies
and the ascending and descending scale
can potentially be different from each
other which is totally different from
any concept in western music. Then each
raa has a sonent note and a consonant
note. Asant note is the note that you
emphasize the most out of all the other
notes. And the consonant note is the
second most emphasized note. Then you
have drone notes. So when you are
playing raar,
you also have a vina that's accompanying
you in the background. And the vina
it'll be tuned to three notes and those
are the drone notes and that goes on in
the background. Ding ding ding. You keep
plucking that. And by playing this kind
of music it it will create create an
atmosphere, a mood, a set of emotions.
Each raa has a personality of its own.
And each raa is typically associated
with each of the major ragas is
typically associated with some with with
a particular specific deity. For
example, rahav which is a dawn raa which
you play in the early morning when the
sun is rising. that [clears throat] is
generally associated with Lord Shiva
right and other raas are associated with
other gods and there is
and yeah each ra also has a pucker which
is a which is a distinctive melodic
phrase associated with the raa so raas I
mean it's the most incredible
system of music and you can play raas on
modern instruments you can play the play
raas on piano on electric instruments
you can play ragas on guitar. I've done
that. I would love to reconnect with my
musical roots. So, and it obviously some
ragas have, you know, hypnotic,
it can put you in a hypnotic translike
state. Some of them can be good for
meditating. Some of them are said to be
good for healing and so on. So, it's
it's a very deep and profound subject. I
can't explain in 5 minutes. Maybe I
should have a musician come and talk to
me about this, you know, have a
conversation. Maybe I should revive the
podcast just for that. Let's see. We'll
see about that. Okay, that's the last
question from the comments. Let's see
some questions from the live chat if we
have any. Okay, I see that we have three
super chats. Let me deal with those
first of all. UMX says that is it true
that anyone west of Persia was called
Mletcha in ancient India and it meant
that there were foreigners and who were
considered outside the realms of Vic
Dharma, a word similar to Kafir? No.
What did Mletcher mean in the Indian
civilizational concept?
The Mletcher word the word Mletcher was
the opposite of the word Arya. In our
context, the Indian civilizational
concept. The word Arya meant noble,
civilized
and Gletcher meant univilized.
So it essentially meant whoever
was no longer following
the Vic lifestyle, the precepts of the
Vedas, that person was called called a
Mletcha. Irrespective of race, skin
color, eye color, hair color, it had
nothing to do with your race or
ethnicity. If you had blonde hair and
blue eyes, but you practiced the Vic
lifestyle, then you were an Arya, not a
bleacher.
So those who had moved away from the
precepts of the Vedas, they were called
lechas including our own people who had
migrated to central Asia and wherever
else. So that
could potentially include Persians when
they moved away from the Vic lifestyle,
right? Yeah. And Yavana, what does the
word Yavana mean? It means Ionian.
There's something called the Ionian Sea.
Let me show you what is the Ionian Sea.
Okay, let's go here to the map. Where is
the Ionian Sea? Okay, let's find the
Ionian Sea, shall we?
So, here we have the Ionian Sea between
Greece and Italy.
So, the people who lived in this region
were called were called the Ionians and
we called them the Yavanas.
All right. So yavana means Greek
essentially. It has nothing to do with
this term cafe or whatever the hell that
is. Nothing to do with that.
Right. Next question. Sumid says please
write elillutive book on Indian history
timeline.
I'll put that on my to-do list. Maybe it
is already there on my to-do list. Well
thank you for the suggestion sir. ICMBBS
says are ex US colonies fairing better
than French ones? Well, the UK colonies,
who did the UK colonize? India,
Australia,
uh, etc. Just these two also West Asia,
you know, Middle East, Egypt, and so on.
But let's talk about India, Australia.
So, overall, if you look at these
countries, they're doing better than the
countries the French colonized, which
are the countries in the Sahil region,
Africa, and so on. Those were
devastated.
So, I'm not sure it's it's because the
the British were better than the French.
I'm not sure about that. It's because we
were more resilient than the poor
African people who were devastated by
the other Europeans, the French. That's
what it means. So, please don't mistake
it to to mean that the the British were
better than the French. No, they had the
same objectives. They had the same
method essentially.
They employed the same methodologies for
for for occupy occupying and plundering.
But the effect was different. We were
more resilient. That's why we used to we
rebounded and we are in the process of
maybe rising again as as a great power.
Africa totally devastated because they
perhaps were less resilient. I'm not
sure. Right. So that's the deal.
Okay, let's take perhaps some questions.
Okay, I will not please stop taking
super chats. This is not a super chat
live stream but I'll take the super
chats which are already there. Um Akshit
Raj says I a new subscriber. Well, thank
you so much Akshit. Welcome and I'm glad
to have you as a subscriber, sir. I
wanted to know about my about your views
on David Reich's AMT.
You can call it whatever you want. Arian
invasion theory, which is AIT or if that
doesn't work, invasion doesn't work,
well, let's call it a migration
migration theory. If migration doesn't
work, we'll call it
tourism theory. If tourism doesn't work,
we we will call it picnic theory. This
is a bunch of nonsense.
Okay. And I have entire Ask Kabijit live
streams dedicated to this RN invasion
nonsense. Okay. And I don't say it's
nonsense because I am emotional about
this and I hate this.
I before 2016 I used to believe that
there was an RN invasion of India. I
used to believe it. But then one day I
said let me look into it. Let me look
into not what people are saying, not
what historians are writing, but let me
look at the actual evidence, the hard
evidence, archaeological evidence,
literary evidence, genetic evidence. And
when I spent a few months looking into
it in great detail, I discovered there
is no evidence whatsoever that supports
an invasion or migration or tourism or
picnic of India by some some
white-kinned Arians. Nothing.
And I have entire episodes dedicated to
the Arian invasion myth. Um what is the
episode number? I can look into that.
Maybe I can um if you want know to know
my views in detail, we can look into
that. So let me see. Uh let's let's look
at my channel
and uh let's see where is this episode.
Which episode is that? Let us see. Live
stream. Live stream. Live stream. Live
stream. uh this one 43 arian invasion
migration tourism picnic that's the one
so check out that that episode in which
you will find
exactly what my views are about this
matter and now I have more live super
chats people are taking please please
let let us end this live stream soon
okay let's see says one last question
the westerners and Americans really
believe that they are the modern-day
descendants of the Roman Empire and
civilization we can see that in their
symbolism is any truth to that? Any
truth to that?
The Romans, their descendants
are the Italians.
No one else. The Romans did occupy much
of Europe and even North Africa and they
may have left behind a little bit of
their genetic material there. May
happens
that way. Everyone is related to the
Romans, right?
If you look at northern and western
India, you will have lots of people who
will have maybe 1% Greek ancestry,
maybe 3% scheian ancestry, maybe 2%
Kushan ancestry.
That way, everyone's related to each
other.
Genetically,
everybody is related to each other and
every, you know, most people in Europe
will have some little bit little amount
of potential Roman ancestry.
But are they civilizationally
carrying the legacy of the Roman Empire?
Well, then you would ask yourself, was
Rome a civilization or an empire? It was
an empire. It was not a civilization.
Okay, Greece was a civilization that the
Romans conquered. And Greece lost its
sovereignty 2,150 years ago. It has
never regained it.
Um, so
the Americans are not modern-day
descendants of the Roman Empire, which
was not a civilization. They are the
descendants
of the Anglo, not the Anglo-Saxons, the
the the English, who are a combination
of three races.
The people of the UK, let's say the
English, they are a combination of three
races. One, the Kelts, the Celtic
people. Second,
the Anglo-Saxons
who invaded and conquered the island uh
in the middle of the first millennium
AD. And thirdly, the Normans who were
originally of of Nordic origin. These
three races mixed and gave rise to the
modernday people of the UK, mainly the
English. The Americans are are
descendants of those people. Of course
they have absorbed other it is now.
But which civilization is the west a
descendant of? None.
None. The west is an empire. If you want
to call it a cohesive entity, it's an
empire because Christianity was not a
civilization. It itself was an imperial
system.
And
the west was not in any way a
continuation of ancient Greece. They
destroyed everything that Greece stood
for and imposed Christianity on top of
that. So they can't claim descent from
Greece. The Romans can legitimately
claim connection to Greece because they
absorbed Greek culture and made their
own. The Romans did. But the Romans were
polytheists and Christianity is a
reputation of everything polytheistic.
So how can you then claim that you are a
continuation of Rome when you hate
polytheism?
Right? So they see it's it's all about
acquiring some of the prestige without
without acquiring the polytheistic and
idolatory practices of of of the Romans
and Greeks. So we want the prestige
associated with Rome, but we don't want
the evil polytheism. We don't want the
evil idol worship.
That's the deal about the West and the
United States.
UX says, "Aren't non-Muslims of any race
called Kafir?" Well, the non the Muslims
will call non-Muslims kafir. What does
it have to do with us?
What's the argument here sir?
The mchea thing
that that that is nothing to do with any
kafir nonsense thing. Okay, that that's
a totally different thing. The mch like
I explained mchletcha means nonaria.
Arya means noble and civilized. Lecha
means someone who has moved away from
the Vic way of life. It has nothing to
do with the Islamic concept of kafir or
whatever. You may see some parallels in
that. I do not. Okay.
Okay. Um
I can now say that there's a
thousands of questions that people have
here.
Let's take maybe a couple of this. Nirj
says our textbooks say that we had
pre-classified occupation
based on cast but Peshwa Bajira was a
warrior despite being a Brahman.
Please do not believe anything your
history textbooks tell you. They are
lying. They distorting our history. We
had various kings who were proud to be
of sudra origin. Sudra did not mean
something bad.
And you had social mobility in India.
Like you have pointed out here, Bishwa
Baji was a Brahman but he decided to
become a warrior. Life decided that he
has to become a warrior. So he became a
warrior and through his deeds as a
warrior he became a chhatria.
That was the deal in India in our
civilization. We had social mobility. We
do not have that rigid horrific cast
system that I that I discussed earlier
that the Europeans had
that was based your station in in
society and life is divinely ordained by
the God by the one Christian God and if
you question that if you try to be
socially mobile
you are committing a sin against God and
you must be burned alive. We did not
have any of that. Right? So if your
textbooks are telling you that we had
some that sort of thing your textbooks
are lying to you. Everything that is
today considered to be self-evident
truth is based on collodial atrocity
literature to make you hate your own
ancestors and to be ashamed of your own
culture. That is the objective.
Okay.
Amisha says Patnak says Chanaki is an
imaginary person in his recent article.
Uh
well that's his opinion and I do not
take Mr. Patnak seriously and neither
should anybody else. That gentleman has
a very
very clear agenda.
He is a disciple of Wendy Doniger who
wrote that horrific book about the
Hindus.
So that explains what kind of gentleman
Shri Patnak G is. So I do not take him
seriously at all and uh yeah that's all
I can say about Mr. Patnak and his
opinions.
Right. Okay.
Geopoliticis control s control I shall
control. Yes. Thank you sir. Uh
Chatanya says eyewitnesses claim that
2611 shooters were white or foreign
looking. Even JK that said there were
more than terrorist 10 terrorists. What
are my thoughts? I I I have not looked
into this. I have not looked into this.
So I cannot say say anything about this.
Can't say.
Uh
Pax Shield says who are the most
diabolical in history? French, Spanish,
English,
Turkish invaders, Khalifs. I would say
the most diabolical in history were the
English and the Turk invaders.
Okay. Um
okay, let's take this one last question
for today. Peline lover says, "Hixos
people who invaded Egypt actually the
Skyians.
Are the Hixos actually the Skyians? And
could Hixos be a corruption of Skitians
becoming s becoming a lot of Hixos names
do sound more Indo-aranian than Sematic?
I'm not sure about the Skithian angle.
The Skithians were obviously Indo Indo
Iranian people. Their names were very
much
you know in sync with Indian and Persian
names.
Um a bunch of names they had the
skitians parata was one of their kings.
It sounds very Sanskrit doesn't it? Um
could the hixos be skitian s becoming h.
Well the term skitian is is a term in
the English language. The true term is
shaka. That's what we called them.
That's what the Persians called them.
The Persians called them shaker. Not
skitans.
The Indians us we call them shaker. Not
in not Skiians. It's an English word.
The Egyptians, if they had known the
Skithians, they would have either have
called them the Shakas or some Egyptian
word. They would have not not invented
an Egyp an English word and use that.
Right? English the English language that
is spoken today did not even exist two
and a what when was that? Three and a
half thousand years ago.
Right? So it's it's not possible. Now
um so who the the Hixos names many of
them do sound more Indo-arian than
somiting no question about it their way
of life their way of warfare all of that
looks very indo indooran the
the kind of boughs they used the kind of
weapons they used the the the bronze
ax the pu the chariots they used they
had one sari and one Maharati the jav I
mean the god they worshiped
a god of thunder and rain everything
sounds very Indo-arian but the consensus
among scholars is that they were smiting
people so what can I say there was okay
we have one more super chat which I
shall take
and this is going to be the last
question of the day even if there are
more super chats I won't be able to take
them today so this is the last question
of today devil x says do you think our
textbooks will change showing the true
history after India becomes a major 10
to15 trillion dollar economy.
I have no idea. It depends on the
leadership not on the economy. The
leadership must have political will to
change the nonsense that is being
you know imparted in the name of
education.
That has to happen. But maybe leadership
if if you become a 10 15 trillion dollar
economy maybe the leadership will also
be different perhaps. So it will depend
on the leadership not on the economy but
economy leadership are also
interconnected. So I'm hopeful this will
happen. But why hasn't it already
happened in the past 10 years? What has
prevented this government from doing it?
I don't understand.
I'm sure they have
bigger things to worry about. I'm sure
no question about that. But this is also
important. It is poisoning the hearts
and minds of our own people of our own
youngsters.
Our our youngsters are not evil people
but they are they are being brainwashed
into hating their own culture their own
civilization their own ancestors right
it needs to change but there isn't any
political will today hopefully hopefully
I'm hopeful I'm an ever optimistic
person so hopefully when we are a 10 to
15 trillion dollar economy things will
change I hope so I hope so let us all
hope and pray to the great gods
including Shri Indra for that.
All right people, thank you so much for
this live stream for all the questions
and uh there were so many great
questions that you all asked in the
comments. I think I'll have to do more
extra additional live streams about
about history to cover all of those but
I'm going to end this here. Thank you
everybody. Thank you very much. It is
great to be back on the Ask a Bajget
show after a break of a few days. And
tomorrow we're going to have a live
stream about geopolitics. It's going to
be a super chat live stream. I look
forward to seeing you all there
tomorrow. Until then, take care. Keep
asking questions. Keep learning. Keep
raising your standards. See you
tomorrow. Bye-bye.